<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <podcast:guid>5C339F5A-DA10-470C-B3D7-8C210B994FEA</podcast:guid>
    <title>Cris's txtpod</title>
    <link>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <itunes:author>Cris</itunes:author>
    <description>A podcast generated by txtpod.</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/icon.png</url>
      <title>Cristian's txtpod</title>
      <link>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod</link>
    </image>
    <itunes:image href="https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/icon.png"/>
    <podcast:location>www.txtpod.com</podcast:location>
    <license>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International</license>
    <atom:link href="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  
            <item>
      <title>Slate Auto’s American-made electric</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Slate Auto’s American-made electric pickup — the one with no paint, no stereo, and no touchscreen — is no longer priced “under $20,000.” The increase is a result of Trump’s “Big, beautiful bill,” which will end the federal EV tax credits on September 30th when signed into law later today. That sub-$20,000 price for the Indiana-built pickup was a big selling point for the EV startup backed by Jeff Bezos, and was only possible after applying the $7,500 tax credit to the retail price. The price promotion was scrubbed from the Slate Auto site as recently as yesterday, according to TechCrunch. The website now shows an expected price of “mid-twenties.” Slate’s under $20,000 price tag for a vehicle it won’t start delivering until late 2026 was always accompanied by an asterisk, with fine print highlighting federal incentives that were “subject to change.” And change was certainly expected: Trump campaigned heavily on the promise to end President Biden’s fictitious “EV mandate,” because electric cars are for socialists in MAGA world. Trump’s embrace of oil and gas, while simultaneously dismantling incentives meant to spur the adoption of EVs and clean energies, is a gift to Chinese makers of electric cars, solar panels, and batteries. The US is now on course to own the past while China is firmly positioned to dominate the future. See More: Electric Cars News Policy Transportation]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:37:57 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-37-57.wav" length="4372244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>91</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-37-57.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>It’s been almost two</title>
      <description><![CDATA[It’s been almost two years since a brand new Apple Watch Ultra model launched, but that drought is almost over. Apple Watch Ultra 3’s release date is fast approaching, here’s when to expect the new model. Last year, Apple did not launch a new Ultra model. Instead, it just released a new satin black titanium finish for the Ultra 2. But reporting from various sources indicates this is the year for a brand new model. Apple Watch Ultra 3 is expected to launch this September. Based on well-established patterns, we can get even more precise with the timing. Apple usually kicks off the fall with a big iPhone and Apple Watch-focused event. The most likely date for that event is right around Monday, September 8. Pre-orders for the Apple Watch Ultra 3 will likely begin that week, with the release date being the following Friday, September 19. Apple’s plans could always change, but it has followed a pretty consistent pattern with previous Apple Watch launches. As a result, an Apple Watch Ultra 3 release date in mid-September is highly likely. Apple Watch Ultra 3 is rumored to include a handful of new features. Apple will likely have several more surprises in store too. First, the Ultra 3 is expected to gain display and chip upgrades that it missed out on last year. When the Apple Watch Series 10 arrived last fall, it included a new LTPO3 OLED display. This enabled more frequent refreshes in always-on mode, plus improved viewing from angles. Apple Watch Ultra 3 should gain the same technology this year. Similarly, the Series 10 debuted a new S10 chip, while the Ultra 2 still has the S9. Expect the Ultra 3 to either get Apple’s S10 or a brand new S11—perhaps with AI optimizations for watchOS 26. Outside of playing catch-up to the Series 10, there are three other brand new features rumored for the Ultra 3: High blood pressure detection Satellite connectivity for Messages 5G cellular New health sensors and connectivity features should make the Apple Watch Ultra 3 a better option than ever for adventurers and explorers. Are you planning to buy an Apple Watch Ultra 3 this year? Why or why not? Let us know in the comments. FTC: We use income earning auto affiliate links. More.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-38-01.wav" length="6903644" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>143</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-38-01.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>For the past two</title>
      <description><![CDATA[For the past two years, Apple has been having a tough time in China. Just recently, the U.S. trade war and local incentives from the Chinese government really got in the way of iPhone sales. However, Apple seems to be regaining control of the situation. As we covered recently, Apple’s extended rough patch in China may finally be easing. Since Q3 2022, the company has posted year-over-year revenue growth in just one quarter, with declines of up to 13% in the others. Not great. Things hit a low point a couple of months ago, at the peak of U.S.–China trade tensions. To make matters worse, local government incentives for domestic brands chipped away at Apple’s market share, making it the only major smartphone maker to report a decline in shipments during Q1. From that point on, things started to look a bit better. iPhone sales picked up (slightly) in April, Apple gave in and joined the Chinese government’s subsidy program, and it started to see early signs of a rebound last month. Now, Counterpoint Research is out with a new report (via CNBC)that doubles down on its earlier indication of a turnaround. It claims that Apple saw an 8% rise in iPhone sales in the quarter ending June, a first in two years. Here’s Ethan Qi, associate director at Counterpoint: “Apple’s adjustment of iPhone prices in May was well timed and well received, coming a week ahead of the 618 shopping festival.” As CNBC explains it: “The 618 shopping festival happens in China every June and e-commerce retailers offer heavy discounts.” The report comes on the heels of Apple’s scheduling of its fiscal Q3 earnings results. It will take place on July 31st, and will cover precisely the months of April, May, and June. FTC: We use income earning auto affiliate links. More.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:39:34 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-39-34.wav" length="5650244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>117</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-39-34.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Social media is full</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Social media is full of images of people plunging into freezing lakes and icy baths, with influencers touting the benefits of cold exposure in one form or another. You may have been wondering what it’s all about and whether should you try it. As a qualified cold-water therapist, allow me to take you through my own journey with the cold – and then I’ll show you how to give it a try. Until recent years, I had little interest in being outdoors, let alone swimming in freezing waters. Pop me on a hot beach with a fruity drink, and I was in my element. This changed, rather drastically, five years ago, starting with the diagnosis of my mother’s terminal cancer. I didn’t realise it at the time, but this news, coupled with a change to my job and months of homeschooling, uncertainty and lockdowns during the COVID-19 pandemic, set me on a path of very poor mental health. Come Christmas 2020, I was completely burnt out. I was prescribed antidepressants and anti-anxiety medication, but they made no difference. I spent a few more months barely coping, when my brother suggested a cold-water dip. This seemed ludicrous: I’d always hated being cold. But after discussing it with my GP, and desperate to give anything a try, I went with my brother to Loch of Clunie, Perthshire in Scotland – his hometown. I felt nervous as I anticipated the freezing cold water rushing into my borrowed wetsuit. Stepping into the loch, I gasped and froze as adrenaline pumped through me. Never one for quitting, I proceeded further until I was in over my shoulders. ‘Jeez, that’s cold, I can’t breathe,’ I gasped. ‘OK, I’m in – I did it. Wow, I did it! That’s amazing.’ It’s a cliché, but it really was as if a switch had been flicked. I realised I had experienced a few moments of controlled thought (aka, mindfulness), a skill I thought I had lost forever to my new, anxiety-ridden brain. I felt proud of myself, and I experienced happiness for the first time in almost a year. I felt compelled to understand my experience. I read reports, research papers and any books that were even loosely based on cold therapy. Although cold water as a medicinal therapy is far from a new concept (notable figures from ancient history, such as Hippocrates, are known to have advocated for it), the formal scientific research into its benefits, including for mental health, is still in its infancy. But the research we do have all points in the same positive direction, and I’ve found this is consistently backed up by anecdotal feedback from my clients. Cold-water therapy, encompassing practices such as cold-water immersion and ice baths, has been associated with several physical health benefits, according to research. This includes improved circulation and reduced inflammation. However, I think it’s the psychological benefits of cold-water therapy that are driving its growing popularity. There are many layers of reported positive effects and attributes. To take a specific example: in 2022, researchers surveyed 53 participants with a range of depression severity levels before and after they took part in an eight-session outdoor swimming course on the North Devon coast. Afterwards, 81 per cent of them felt ‘recovered’, and 62 per cent showed ‘reliable improvement’ to their mental wellbeing. Of course, the key beneficial ingredients are tricky to pin down. Other studies show that simply getting outdoors, being in green and blue spaces, is good for us. If we swim with others, there are the benefits of human connection and community too. However, there is something special about the effects of cold water on the body and mind. Exposure to cold water provokes positive mood changes and brain changes associated with emotional control; it also triggers the vagus nerve (which runs from your brainstem to your abdominal organs). This nerve stimulates the parasympathetic nervous system, which controls the body’s ‘rest and digest’ functions. It’s basically the opposite of fight or flight. Its activation calms us after stress, slowing our heartrate and breathing pattern. This resonates with my personal experience. After my first cold-water dip, it was only on reflection that I realised how focused on the present moment I had been in the freezing water. That is exactly what mindfulness is – being fully present in the moment. I had previously confused mindfulness with an idealised notion of meditation (where one works to clear the mind of all thought). There were most definitely thoughts in my mind, but instead of the usual anxious worries, it was more: What am I doing? This is cold, wow – look at that bird, oh, this feels OK now (you get the idea). It was such a relief to know that I wasn’t broken beyond repair, and I could indeed tear my thoughts away from worry and angst. The cold water demanded it from me. This was followed by the ‘natural high’ that cold-water swimmers rave about. By continually exposing ourselves to a stressor (the cold water) and overcoming the shock, we are also building resilience, a key tool in the toolkit of good mental health. We are learning to manage stress, and this is cross-adaptive to other stressful life scenarios. One of my earliest experiences of this was at my mother’s funeral, for which I had written a poem to read. As I stood, my mind was racing, legs weak, and I couldn’t speak. I took a moment to close my eyes and channel the calmness that I feel when in cold water. I imagined myself in the water, breathed as I would in the cold and, after a minute, was able to talk. Many of my clients have shared similar stories of how they feel better equipped to deal with difficult situations because they have habituated themselves to stress. Do you feel ready to give cold-water therapy a try? Here are some practical steps, starting gently and building up to a cold-water swim. Because cold-water immersion can be dangerous for people with certain medical conditions, please remember to check with your doctor first. Has anyone ever advised you to splash cold water on your face and neck after you’ve been angry, upset or stressed? There’s a scientific reason it might help. The application of cold to the back of the neck is a quick and easy method for stimulating the vagus nerve. A more dramatic effect can be achieved by fully immersing your face in cold water, which triggers the trigeminal nerve (the fifth cranial nerve) in your face, which then signals to your brain that you’re underwater. In turn, this activates the vagus nerve, to slow your heart rate and breathing. This is known as the ‘mammalian dive reflex’. It’s another easy method of using cold water to reduce stress. You will find all sorts of cold-shower plans if you look online, differing depending on the aims. Some people will be using them as a method of acclimatising to the cold – working up to cold-water swimming or ice baths. But you can use your shower as a standalone method of cold exposure. Remember that the calming benefits of cold-water immersion come after the initial shock. That’s why it’s important to develop a practice that works toward you being comfortable in the cold – at least for a short while. Although it might be unavoidable at first, if you jump around and scream and shout the whole time, you’re just staying in the stressor part of the experience, and may not gain the maximum benefits. Take a stopwatch into the shower. Start with a warm shower as normal. Then slowly reduce the water temperature. There is no formal definition of what counts as cold water, but scientists researching cold-water benefits usually take 15°C (60°F) or lower as cold. You may need to work down to this over time. As a rough guide, try turning down the temperature until it feels slightly uncomfortable and triggers a gasp breath. As your gasp reflex kicks in – breathe! Do not practise any form of forced breathwork (this can be highly dangerous in water as you may pass out), but just aim to control your breath. Inhale through your nose and out of your mouth. I often find that a noisy breath helps me to maintain a good pattern. Try to stay under at least until you feel the shock subside. Don’t set yourself a target duration after that, but do have your stopwatch running so you can see how long you were in for. Over time and with daily practice, you will likely notice your initial shock response subsides and that you are able to tolerate the cold for longer. Some say that the best time to take a cold shower is in the morning to kick-start your system. Personally, I find a cold shower more of a challenge than an ice bath or outdoor swim. Maybe it’s because I’m not fully submerged the whole time? Just as soon as the front of my body gets comfortable, I then have to turn round and start all over again on my back! Having your body fully submerged in the cold is the ultimate cold-water exposure. It doesn’t matter whether you’re in the sea, a river, a lake, an outdoor pool (or even a purpose-made ice bath), cold water is cold water. It’s the safety precautions that vary hugely in different bodies of water. Never go alone. Wetsuits are optional. You will still experience some level of cold exposure and, if a neoprene suit helps you to overcome any initial fears, and gets you outdoors, then use it (you can always ditch the suit later for maximum cold exposure). For obvious reasons, it’s often easier to start at the ‘warmer end’ of cold – around 15°C (as a rough guide, this is the kind of temperature you might expect swimming off the Pacific Coast in early summer in the US, or sea swimming in early summer in the UK, or off an Australian beach in the winter). This will help you to acclimatise and prepare gradually for colder temperatures. Try to go weekly as a minimum. There’s no proven research on how regularly you need to participate, but I find once a week is satisfactory, and that two to three times a week is optimal. If I don’t manage to get in the water for two weeks or more, I find that I start to lose some of my tolerance. How cold should you go? Endorphins are the primary natural painkillers in the body and improve mood. It could be suggested that colder water will produce greater endorphins. Many of my clients report a higher state of euphoria after dipping in icy waters, but many of them started their cold-water journeys in warmer water and worked towards ice-dipping. Even after a medical check-up, you never know how your body will react, and the safest advice is to take things gradually and see what works for you. Always enter slowly. Yes, this can feel like more of a challenge, but it will allow you to keep control and put the least pressure on your heart. If you are in a natural body of water, take it in stages. Get your feet in and stand for a moment. Take a controlled breath. Wade in until you’re above the knees. Take a moment – notice the cold and turn to your breath. You may find you’re holding your breath at this stage. Concentrate on breathing in through the nose and out through the mouth. You must be mindful that, although you are not rushing, you also don’t want to take too long to get in. Our bodies lose heat up to 25 times faster in cold water. Next, aim to get waist deep. At the point that some of your most sensitive areas are going to hit the water, inhale, step forward (or crouch lower in your ice bath) and use your out-breath to get them in. The groin, underarms and neck are usually our warmer spots, and the contrast can feel greater. Continue to breathe calmly until any shock or gasp reflex has lessened. Finally, it is your aim to get fully immersed. By this, I mean in up to your neck (do not submerge your head or face when starting out). Again, use your breath, inhale, then plunge down until the water hits your neck on the exhale. Sit with it and maintain your breathing. Once you are breathing normally, you have gone past the stress, and your parasympathetic nervous system is fully activated. If you’re just starting out, this is when you need to be thinking about getting out. Two to three minutes is likely long enough to get over the cold shock response and resume ‘normal’ breathing. Do not try to ‘stay in longer’ than this or challenge yourself to do more. There is really no need when you are simply using the cold as a form of therapy. If at any point it’s too difficult or if you feel unwell, stop immediately. Following cold-water exposure, you must always remove wet clothing, dry yourself and dress immediately. It takes time for the re-warming process to start, and you must support the process. Gentle movement, such as walking, is most effective to help with re-warming. Cold-water exposure can be dangerous and comes with risks. Everyone responds differently. I recommend seeking an experienced, qualified and insured practitioner if you want to undertake an ice bath or outdoor plunge for the first time in low temperatures. As mentioned, everyone should also seek medical approval before participating, but it’s especially important for people with cardiovascular conditions, respiratory issues or cold-related allergies. We work hard to bring you the most trustworthy, expert and up-to-date information on psychology and mental health in our Guides. You can learn more about how we ensure that they are a reliable source of information here. This Guide is provided as general information only. It is not a substitute for independent, professional medical or health advice tailored to your specific circumstances. If you are struggling with psychological difficulties, we encourage you to seek help from a professional source.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:05:18 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-05-18.wav" length="40342244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>840</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-05-18.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>La tensión y la</title>
      <description><![CDATA[La tensión y la incertidumbre marcan la primera sesión del juicio por el crimen de Valentín Moreno. Las versiones ofrecidas por los dos principales acusados no solo son contradictorias, sino diametralmente opuestas, lo que ha sumido la sala en un clima de confusión y expectativa. Mientras Daniel Díaz Mora ha admitido sin rodeos ser el autor material del asesinato, alegando que actuó por orden de Sergio Gutiérrez, este último ha negado tajantemente cualquier implicación y, aún más, asegura no conocer “de nada” al presunto sicario. La distancia entre sus relatos no puede ser más extrema. Por un lado, Díaz Mora, colombiano, ha reconocido que disparó a Valentín Moreno por la espalda. Señalando a Gutiérrez como el intermediario clave y supuesto cooperador necesario en el crimen. Por otro lado, Sergio Gutiérrez, el segundo acusado, ha ofrecido una versión totalmente distinta: asegura que fue engañado y que, lejos de participar en el asesinato, creía estar colaborando con un grupo de colombianos en un asunto vinculado al narcotráfico. Niega rotundamente haber tenido conocimiento del homicidio o haber mantenido relación alguna con Díaz. En el banquillo de los acusados: Daniel Díaz Mora (izquierda) y Sergio Gutiérrez Martín (derecha) entre dos agentes de los Mossos d'Esquadra Crónica Global Seguimientos por una deuda de dinero De este modo, Daniel Díaz Mora, el hombre acusado de asesinar a Valentín Moreno, ha reconocido ante el tribunal y los miembros del jurado que fue él quien le disparó en la nuca, la tarde del 18 de noviembre de 2021. Durante su declaración ha explicado que un amigo suyo de la infancia, Alexander, le contactó a principios de noviembre de ese año para realizar “un trabajo” en España. Según su versión, Alexander le propuso realizar un seguimiento a una persona a cambio de 5.000 euros, además de cubrir los gastos del viaje. Aceptando, dice, por necesidad económica. Viajó de Medellín a Barcelona, donde se alojó junto a Alexander en un piso cercano a la Sagrada Familia. Al día siguiente de su llegada, ambos conocieron a Sergio Gutiérrez quien les explicó que debían seguir a un individuo por una supuesta deuda de dinero. Ese individuo era Valentín Moreno. Según Díaz Mora, nunca se le habló directamente de un asesinato, sino únicamente de realizar un seguimiento. Monitorizaron la vida de Moreno Según su versión, Sergio les condujo hasta la casa de Moreno, así como al gimnasio y los bares que frecuentaba. Tras conocer los lugares de referencia del objetivo se iniciaron las vigilancias. Para evitar levantar sospechas, utilizaron patinetes eléctricos alquilados con un documento de identidad robado, facilitado por Sergio. Fue así como, según su relato de los hechos, Daniel y Alexander monitorearon los movimientos diarios de Moreno mientras iban reportando la información recibida. Valentín Moreno, en círculo rojo, con el resto del equipo del Sant Adrià CF Cedida "Le hago un disparo en la cabeza" Sin embargo, la tarde del 18 de noviembre de 2021, lo que comenzó como una tarea de vigilancia derivó en una ejecución. Según su testimonio, Alexander lo citó cerca del bar que frecuentaba la víctima. En ese momento, y bajo amenazas contra su familia, Díaz Mora accedió a participar en el asesinato. Recibió un maletín con una pistola cargada con silenciador, se subió a una bicicleta y siguió a Valentín durante varias calles. Cuando este salió de su coche, le disparó por la espalda, directamente en la nuca. “Le hago un disparo en la cabeza”, ha reconocido. Tras el crimen, Alexander lo recogió en una motocicleta y se encargó de deshacerse del arma. Ambos se dirigieron a un punto donde los esperaba Sergio, visiblemente alterado. Al día siguiente volvieron a Medellín con unos billetes que ya tenían comprados previamente. Valentín Moreno, el homicida de la Vila Olímpica, durante un juicio EFE La versión del presunto cooperador A continuación ha sido el turno de Sergio Gutiérrez. Visiblemente nervioso, ha comenzado su declaración asegurando que no conoce “de nada” a Daniel Díaz Mora, a quien afirma no haber visto en su vida. En tono tajante, ha acusado al otro procesado de mentir deliberadamente para obtener un pacto con la Fiscalía, que —según ha confirmado— también le ofrecieron a él. Sin embargo, Gutiérrez asegura que no puede aceptar un acuerdo porque no puede admitir un crimen que no ha cometido. En su lugar, ha ofrecido una versión completamente distinta de su implicación en los hechos, una que —según dice— tiene su origen en un asunto relacionado con el narcotráfico. Según su testimonio, tras salir de prisión por una condena vinculada al tráfico de drogas, se puso en contacto con Cristian Rus, con la intención de volver a buscarse la vida en el mundo de la droga. Rus le prometió que hablaría con Javier Gómez, alias Javidubi, para ver si podía echarle una mano. Dos presuntos colombianos narcos Poco después, Cristian Rus le presentó a Gómez, quien se había hecho muy popular por su vinculación con los Boixos Nois. Fue entonces cuando Javidubi le comentó que dos colombianos “muy potentes” iban a llegar a Barcelona por un negocio de narcotráfico, concretamente para controlar una carga en el Puerto de la ciudad. Su función, según declaró, se limitaría exclusivamente a buscarles alojamiento. Así, consiguió un piso turístico en las inmediaciones de la Sagrada Familia, donde se instalarían los supuestos colombianos. Javidubi, quien según Gutiérrez no tenía un rol operativo en el envío, pero sí interés en que todo saliera bien, le advirtió que los recién llegados venían “a controlar el terreno” y a supervisar la llegada de un contenedor. A principios de noviembre, recibió un mensaje: “Ha llegado uno de los colombianos”, le advirtió Javidubi. Quedaron en un bar cercano al piso. Allí, según relató, estaban ya presentes Alexander —la misma persona que Díaz Mora señala como quien le propuso el crimen— y Javi. Gutiérrez llegó algo más tarde. Durante el encuentro, conversaron con discreción sobre temas de “carga y distribución”, sin entrar en detalles. Luego lo acompañó al piso de Sagrada Familia y les ayudó a encontrar un coche con el que moverse por la ciudad. El abogado señala a 'Javidubi' Previamente, durante la intervención de su abogado defensor, este ha recalcado que su cliente no tenía ningún conflicto personal con Valentín Moreno ni interés alguno en su muerte. Sin embargo, ha señalado que sí había al menos dos personas que podrían haber tenido motivos: Cristian Rus y Javier Gómez, Javidubi. El letrado ha insinuado que ambos, que en el pasado habían sido íntimo de Moreno, podrían haber estado más implicados de lo que hasta ahora se ha podido acreditar en el proceso. Tanto Rus como Gómez están citados a declarar este viernes en calidad de testigos.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:37:55 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-37-55.wav" length="23946044" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>498</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-37-55.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>iOS 26’s Messages app</title>
      <description><![CDATA[iOS 26’s Messages app has a solution coming for unwanted texts

Apple’s Messages app got a lot of new features last year, but iOS 26 continues the trend of big upgrades, including a handy solution for all those unwanted spam texts you keep getting. Messages can automatically screen your texts for spam in iOS 26 iOS 26’s Liquid Glass design may be getting the most attention, but the iPhone’s next big update also has lots of new app features coming. These include changes to Apple Wallet, Music, Notes, Reminders, Photos, and more. Apple’s Messages app is getting a big update too. Messages in iOS 26 gets conversation backgrounds, group typing indicators, polls, live translation, and more. One new addition should solve a common frustration for users: unwanted spam texts. As part of Apple’s broader initiative to combat spam outreach, iOS 26 provides the option of silencing texts from unknown numbers and hiding them inside a separate area inside Messages. When using iOS 26, the Messages app will ask you if you’d like to use the new screening tool to filter out texts that are detected as possible spam. If you enable the feature, two changes will take effect: Those texts will no longer alert you via a notification And they’ll get hidden in a separate section of the app Silencing notifications is a great change that limits unwanted interruptions of your time and attention. But you’ll still be able to access those texts if you need to. Via the filtering tool in the top-right corner of Messages, you can switch between different types of texts. Four sections are available: Messages Unknown Senders Spam Recently Deleted iOS 26 offers the option of separately enabling or disabling screening for both Unknown Senders and Spam. Even though texts from unknown senders no longer appear in your main conversations view, you’ll still get a visual prompt on the filters button when there’s a screened text you may want to check. That way, anything mistakenly pushed out of the main view can be discovered before much time passes. Do you plan to use iOS 26’s new spam screening tools in Messages? Let us know in the comments. FTC: We use income earning auto affiliate links. More.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:44:17 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-44-17.wav" length="6844244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>142</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-44-17.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Slate Auto’s electric pickup is no longer ‘under $20,000’ — thanks, Donald</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Slate Auto’s electric pickup is no longer ‘under $20,000’ — thanks, Donald

Slate Auto’s American-made electric pickup — the one with no paint, no stereo, and no touchscreen — is no longer priced “under $20,000.” The increase is a result of Trump’s “Big, beautiful bill,” which will end the federal EV tax credits on September 30th when signed into law later today. That sub-$20,000 price for the Indiana-built pickup was a big selling point for the EV startup backed by Jeff Bezos, and was only possible after applying the $7,500 tax credit to the retail price. The price promotion was scrubbed from the Slate Auto site as recently as yesterday, according to TechCrunch. The website now shows an expected price of “mid-twenties.” Slate’s under $20,000 price tag for a vehicle it won’t start delivering until late 2026 was always accompanied by an asterisk, with fine print highlighting federal incentives that were “subject to change.” And change was certainly expected: Trump campaigned heavily on the promise to end President Biden’s fictitious “EV mandate,” because electric cars are for socialists in MAGA world. Trump’s embrace of oil and gas, while simultaneously dismantling incentives meant to spur the adoption of EVs and clean energies, is a gift to Chinese makers of electric cars, solar panels, and batteries. The US is now on course to own the past while China is firmly positioned to dominate the future. See More: Electric Cars News Policy Transportation]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:46:46 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-46-46.wav" length="8005884" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>90</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-46-46.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Perhaps more tellingly, you’ve</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Perhaps more tellingly, you’ve

Perhaps more tellingly, you’ve also got to completely ignore the camera. The Magic V5’s triple rear camera module rises almost twice as high as Oppo’s, making the phone feel thicker overall as a result. Superior specs, with higher resolution sensors and faster apertures almost across the board, may justify the extra heft, but it does diminish that “world’s thinnest” claim.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:48:20 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-48-20.wav" length="2167636" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>24</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-48-20.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Apple Watch Ultra 3 release date: When to expect the new model</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Apple Watch Ultra 3 release date: When to expect the new model

It’s been almost two years since a brand new Apple Watch Ultra model launched, but that drought is almost over. Apple Watch Ultra 3’s release date is fast approaching, here’s when to expect the new model. Last year, Apple did not launch a new Ultra model. Instead, it just released a new satin black titanium finish for the Ultra 2. But reporting from various sources indicates this is the year for a brand new model. Apple Watch Ultra 3 is expected to launch this September. Based on well-established patterns, we can get even more precise with the timing. Apple usually kicks off the fall with a big iPhone and Apple Watch-focused event. The most likely date for that event is right around Monday, September 8. Pre-orders for the Apple Watch Ultra 3 will likely begin that week, with the release date being the following Friday, September 19. Apple’s plans could always change, but it has followed a pretty consistent pattern with previous Apple Watch launches. As a result, an Apple Watch Ultra 3 release date in mid-September is highly likely. Apple Watch Ultra 3 is rumored to include a handful of new features. Apple will likely have several more surprises in store too. First, the Ultra 3 is expected to gain display and chip upgrades that it missed out on last year. When the Apple Watch Series 10 arrived last fall, it included a new LTPO3 OLED display. This enabled more frequent refreshes in always-on mode, plus improved viewing from angles. Apple Watch Ultra 3 should gain the same technology this year. Similarly, the Series 10 debuted a new S10 chip, while the Ultra 2 still has the S9. Expect the Ultra 3 to either get Apple’s S10 or a brand new S11—perhaps with AI optimizations for watchOS 26. Outside of playing catch-up to the Series 10, there are three other brand new features rumored for the Ultra 3: High blood pressure detection Satellite connectivity for Messages 5G cellular New health sensors and connectivity features should make the Apple Watch Ultra 3 a better option than ever for adventurers and explorers. Are you planning to buy an Apple Watch Ultra 3 this year? Why or why not? Let us know in the comments. FTC: We use income earning auto affiliate links. More.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:49:12 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-49-17.wav" length="11790040" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>133</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-49-17.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Honor launches the ‘world’s thinnest’ foldable</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Honor launches the ‘world’s thinnest’ foldable

Honor has announced the Magic V5, which it says is the thinnest foldable phone in the world right now — though only if you ignore the raised camera module, and only for its white version. The phone launches today in China, but Honor says an international release is coming “soon.” At 8.8mm thick when folded shut, the V5 is indeed impressively thin, and beats the 8.9mm Oppo Find N5. That 0.1mm difference is imperceptible in practice, though a very slight curvature does help Honor’s phone feel a hair thinner than the Oppo. That’s only true for the phone’s “Ivory White” version though, with the other colors very slightly thicker at 9mm, as their fiber and vegan leather finishes are different to the “special fiber” of the white model. Perhaps more tellingly, you’ve also got to completely ignore the camera. The Magic V5’s triple rear camera module rises almost twice as high as Oppo’s, making the phone feel thicker overall as a result. Superior specs, with higher resolution sensors and faster apertures almost across the board, may justify the extra heft, but it does diminish that “world’s thinnest” claim. When open, the V5’s frame measures 4.1mm, again just beating Oppo’s 4.2mm. It’s worth remembering that neither of these phones are quite as thin as Huawei’s trifold Mate XT when it’s open, dropping to 3.6mm at its thinnest point, a segment that doesn’t have the USB-C port. This battle of the millimeters isn’t new territory for Honor. Before Oppo launched the Find N5 earlier this year, Honor’s Magic V3 was the thinnest foldable on the market. Next week Samsung is expected to reveal a drastically thinner Galaxy Z Fold 7, though it’s likely to be just a little thicker than Honor’s effort. Honor isn’t highlighting it, but the Magic V5 might be the world’s lightest foldable too, or at least seems to share that title with Vivo’s X Fold 5, announced last week — both weigh 217g. If this all sounds like quibbling over a gram here and a fraction of a millimeter there, then that’s because it is. I said back when I reviewed the Oppo Find N5 that it would “mark the start of diminishing returns” for foldable phones, and here we are. Without dropping the USB-C port or adopting an asymmetric design there simply isn’t room for these phones to get meaningfully thinner, so foldable manufacturers are going to have to figure out a new way to generate hype for future launches. Fortunately for Honor, the Magic V5 has strong enough specs to impress regardless. Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 8 Elite powers the phone, together with up to 16GB of RAM and a large 5,820mAh battery. Both screens use 120Hz LTPO OLED panels, there’s wireless charging, and IP58 and IP59 ratings for dust- and water-resistance that’s almost as good as any non-foldable’s. Update, July 2nd: Added confirmation that the non-white models are finished in different materials. See More: Foldable Phones Mobile News Tech]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:12:24 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-12-24.wav" length="15814180" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>179</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-20-12-24.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-12-24.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Paramount Plus slashes prices to $2 for two months</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Paramount Plus slashes prices to $2 for two months

If you’re looking for an affordable way to kick off your July 4th weekend, Paramount Plus has a deal worth checking out. Just in time for the July 17th premiere of the third season of Star Trek: Strange New Worlds, new subscribers can enjoy two months of Paramount Plus Premium (normally $12.99 per month) or Plus Essential (regularly $7.99 a month) for just $0.99 per month as part of the Summer Sale. Either deal includes all the features of the base Paramount Plus Essential plan, but the Paramount Plus Premium plan offers better value by providing extra perks at the same discounted price. Premium grants access to both Paramount Plus and Showtime, so you can stream Star Trek shows as well as Yellowstone prequels 1883 and 1923, Tales of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, The Chi, Dexter, Billions, and Yellowjackets. The plan also includes a wide variety of acclaimed films, ranging from Love Me, Sonic the Hedgehog 3, and Gladiator 2 to classics like The Godfather and Pulp Fiction. Paramount Plus Premium grants you ad-free access to live sports as well as movies and shows from both platforms, including Tales of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, the Yellowstone catalog, Star Trek shows, Sonic the Hedgehog 3, Twin Peaks, Dexter, and more. $1 at Paramount (monthly) What’s more, Paramount Plus Premium will also let you livestream the upcoming 2025 NFL season, watch 24/7 live news from CBS News, and catch UEFA Champions League matches. And unlike the base plan, Premium is ad-free and allows you to download content to your mobile device for offline viewing, making it perfect for streaming on the go. Unfortunately, after the two-month promotion period ends, prices return to normal: $12.99 per month for Paramount Plus Premium or $7.99 for Plus Essential. If you’d rather not pay for either, be sure to set a reminder to cancel. See More: Deals Entertainment Star Trek Streaming Tech TV Shows

By Sheena Vasani]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:22:07 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-22-07.wav" length="11549444" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>130</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-20-22-07.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-22-07.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Microsoft is laying off</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Microsoft is laying off as many as 9,000 employees

Today we are sharing decisions that will impact colleagues across our organization. To position Gaming for enduring success and allow us to focus on strategic growth areas, we will end or decrease work in certain areas of the business and follow Microsoft’s lead in removing layers of management to increase agility and effectiveness. Out of respect for those impacted today, the specifics of today’s notifications and any organizational shifts will be shared by your team leaders in the coming days. I recognize that these changes come at a time when we have more players, games, and gaming hours than ever before. Our platform, hardware, and game roadmap have never looked stronger. The success we’re seeing currently is based on tough decisions we’ve made previously. We must make choices now for continued success in future years and a key part of that strategy is the discipline to prioritize the strongest opportunities. We will protect what is thriving and concentrate effort on areas with the greatest potential, while delivering on the expectations the company has for our business. This focused approach means we can deliver exceptional games and experiences for players for generations to come. Prioritizing our opportunities is essential, but that does not lessen the significance of this moment. Simply put, we would not be where we are today without the time, energy, and creativity of those whose roles are impacted. These decisions are not a reflection of the talent, creativity, and dedication of the people involved. Our momentum is not accidental—it is the result of years of dedicated effort from our teams. HR is working directly with impacted employees to provide severance plan benefits (aligned with local laws), including pay, healthcare coverage, and job placement resources to support their transition. Employees whose roles were eliminated are encouraged to explore open positions across Microsoft Gaming, where their applications will be given priority review. Thank you to everyone who has shaped our culture, our products, and our community. We will move forward with deep appreciation and respect for all who have contributed to this journey. Phil

By Tom Warren]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:41:25 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-41-25.wav" length="6587444" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>137</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-20-41-25.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-41-25.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Google makes it easier</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Google makes it easier to let friends and kids control your smart home

Google Home’s latest update will make it easier to decide who in your household can control your smart home. It comes with a new feature, which Google first started testing last year, that will let you assign people “Admin” and “Member” roles. People with Admin status have full control of all the devices, services, and users within their smart home, while Members can only use “basic” device controls, like watching the live view of a security camera. However, admins can grant Members additional privileges by giving them “Settings” access, allowing for control over device and home-wide settings. Admins can also turn on “Activity” access so Members can keep tabs on device history and recent events, such as a visitor picked up by a doorbell camera. Google is also simplifying the process of adding a child under 13 to the Home app. Once you set up your kid with a Google account through Family Link, you can invite them to your Google Home, which will add them as a Member by default. The previous process involved using either Family Link, Google Home, or Google Assistant settings to add your child’s voice to your smart home before inviting them to your home, and many users struggled to get it to work. It seems Google is now streamlining the process by letting you invite a child to your home through the Google Home app, so long as you add them to your Google family group. See More: Apps Google News Smart Home Tech

By Emma Roth]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:44:46 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-44-46.wav" length="4361444" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>90</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-20-44-46.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-44-46.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Ultra Mobile raised its data caps without a price increase</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Ultra Mobile raised its data caps without a price increase

T-Mobile is bringing some of its Uncarrier energy to Ultra Mobile, the carrier’s international-focused MVNO that operates on its network. It announced that its plans now have slightly higher data caps and more international perks, but with the same prices as before for new and existing subscribers — a rare thing to see these days. The plan with the most notable increase in data cap is its $39-per-month tier, which jumps from 15GB to 24GB per month. It also includes 5GB of data you can use in Mexico before international data roaming charges kick in. If you’re accustomed to churning through a ton of data every month, its $59-per-month unlimited (talk, text, and data) plan is stuffed with more goodies. It includes a combined $20 in international calling and data roaming credits, plus 25GB to use as a mobile hotspot (it previously included 20GB). You’ll also get 100 minutes to call “nearly anywhere,” and either 500 texts or 500MB of roaming data to use while traveling abroad before you have to pay extra. Whichever plan is best for your budget, Ultra Mobile stands out from Mint Mobile and Metro (other T-Mobile-owned MVNOs), as well as other major carriers, by offering more perks for people who call and text folks in countries outside the US. In addition to unlimited talk and text to Mexico, Canada, and the UK, Ultra allows free calls to landlines and mobile phones in China, India, Australia, and many other countries. Plus, all of its plans support Wi-Fi calling, which makes it easy to take calls even if local coverage is spotty.

By Cameron Faulkner]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 21:00:08 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-21-00-08.wav" length="5223044" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>108</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-21-00-08.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-21-00-08.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>E Ink is turning the laptop touchpad into an e-reader for AI apps</title>
      <description><![CDATA[E Ink is turning the laptop touchpad into an e-reader for AI apps

E Ink has developed a new touchpad for laptops featuring the same electronic paper technology found in e-readers. It’s not the first company to look at the ever-growing size of laptop touchpads and see the potential of additional functionality, but instead of serving as a second smaller screen for the computer’s OS, E Ink is positioning its touchpad as a dedicated home for AI applications and assistants.

A mockup image shared by the company features a laptop with a touchpad upgraded with a color E Ink screen similar to what’s in use by devices like the Amazon Kindle Colorsoft. Instead of it being an extension of a laptop’s main screen, E Ink envisions its new touchpad as being a separate place where AI-generated text summaries could appear under your hands while working on a document, or you could maintain a constant conversation with an AI chatbot without having to juggle desktop windows.

E Ink’s display technology only consumes power when it’s being updated. That’s a big benefit given the higher demands of AI tools on a laptop’s battery life.

The idea is reminiscent of laptops that companies like Asus have already released featuring upgraded touchpads that double as secondary displays, but they typically feature smartphone-sized LCD screens that are often too small to effectively use applications designed for larger computer screens. A full color screen under your hands can also be a distraction and potentially reduce a laptop’s battery life. The use of E Ink screens has expanded outside e-readers to include colorful signage and digital notepads, but the technology is still best suited to displaying text.

Similar to Apple’s now discontinued Touch Bar, E Ink also says the touchpad display could provide quick access to frequently used shortcuts, display notifications or the weather, or provide temporary playback controls without having to sacrifice a laptop keyboard’s row of function keys. It would also help reduce battery anxiety, because unlike LCD or OLED panels, E Ink’s display technology only consumes power when it’s being updated. That’s a big benefit given the higher demands of AI tools on a laptop’s battery life.

What’s not currently known are more in-depth technical specifications. Aside from the touchpad potentially using color e-paper displays, E Ink hasn’t revealed if it will adapt one of its current panels, or if it’s developed an entirely new one with increased resolutions. Today’s announcement specifically references compatibility with Intel-based AI PCs, but E Ink didn’t go into details about whether the touchpad display would be powered by a laptop’s primary OS, or if it would feature its own. The company also didn’t provide a timeline for when these touchpads might start showing up in laptops or which hardware makers may be interested.

By Andrew Liszewski]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 21:09:41 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-21-09-41.wav" length="8363444" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>174</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-21-09-41.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-21-09-41.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Congress passes budget to expand mass deportations, cut social services, and stall clean energy</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Congress passes budget to expand mass deportations, cut social services, and stall clean energy

The Republican-controlled US Congress has passed a budget bill that includes cuts to social programs like Medicaid and more funding for Immigrations and Customs Enforcement (ICE), alongside provisions that discourage wind and solar energy production. Passed after a marathon debate in both houses, it will allow President Donald Trump to realize policy goals he’s so far attempted to push through executive orders and Elon Musk’s Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE). Trump intends to sign the bill in a 5PM ET ceremony on Friday, July 4th.

The new budget moves funds away from Medicaid, clean energy tax credits, and other public services and toward Trump’s attempt to mass-deport both documented and undocumented immigrants. The bill extends a number of tax cuts that primarily benefit wealthy Americans while reducing spending and eligibility for Medicaid and the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), likely kicking millions off both programs despite objections from some initial Republican holdouts. Sen. Josh Hawley (R-MO), who ultimately voted for the bill, expressed concerns that “we can’t be cutting health care for working people and for poor people in order to constantly give special tax treatment to corporations and other entities.”

During a period of intense demand for electricity — including from companies like Meta, OpenAI, and other Silicon Valley AI giants — the budget also makes it more difficult for wind and solar companies to receive tax credits. It winds down tax credits for EVs, likely rendering electric options more expensive for car buyers. And it requires the FCC to sell 800MHz of spectrum that will likely be drawn from the 6GHz band, which is currently left free to provide more capacity for Wi-Fi services.

While much of the budget fight concerned Medicaid and the national debt, there were also protracted negotiations over a planned 10-year moratorium on states regulating AI systems. Lawmakers ultimately voted against that rule, which was opposed by not only Democrats but many state-level Republican politicians. An excise tax on wind and solar power companies that couldn’t meet strict requirements barring “material assistance” from certain foreign entities including China was similarly removed, although the bill still deals a serious blow to the renewable energy industry. Congress also scrapped a ban on Medicaid funding for gender-affirming care, though it will deny Medicaid funding to reproductive health care group Planned Parenthood.

Meanwhile, the budget provides $45 billion for immigration detention facilities and around $30 billion for ICE personnel and operations costs, on top of tens of billions of dollars in other immigration enforcement-related funding that the nonprofit American Immigration Council says will overall make ICE “the highest-funded law enforcement agency in the entire federal government.”

This increase will allow Trump to continue an ever-expanding mass deportation program, which has seen masked ICE agents target immigrants in workplaces, courtrooms, and on city streets. The administration has widened its net to catch not only undocumented residents, but people who hold visas or green cards or were granted temporary protected status, as well as naturalized citizens; Trump mused earlier this week that his “next job” could be expelling native-born citizens for crimes like murder and said he would consider deporting his former “First Buddy” Elon Musk. Since the Supreme Court recently denied a nationwide injunction on Trump’s termination of 14th Amendment birthright citizenship, the administration could even target a freshly created class of stateless newborn babies later this month.

In addition to expanding arrests, the funding will likely also help continue the creation of new surveillance and detention systems, like a centralized national citizen database that has been reportedly constructed with help from DOGE. As Congress debated the budget bill this week, Trump toured a newly opened Florida detention center built with FEMA funds; the rapidly erected facility — which Republicans celebrated by releasing merchandise with the nickname “Alligator Alcatraz” — flooded during a rainstorm soon after.

By Adi Robertson]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 21:42:59 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-21-42-59.wav" length="12589844" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>262</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-21-42-59.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-21-42-59.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>The new budget moves funds away</title>
      <description><![CDATA[The new budget moves funds away

The new budget moves funds away from Medicaid, clean energy tax credits, and other public services and toward Trump’s attempt to mass-deport both documented and undocumented immigrants. The bill extends a number of tax cuts that primarily benefit wealthy Americans while reducing spending and eligibility for Medicaid and the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 23:23:52 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-23-23-52.wav" length="1176644" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>24</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-23-23-52.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>The new budget moves funds away</title>
      <description><![CDATA[The new budget moves funds away

The new budget moves funds away from Medicaid, clean energy tax credits, and other public services and toward Trump’s attempt to mass-deport both documented and undocumented immigrants. The bill extends a number of tax cuts that primarily benefit wealthy Americans while reducing spending and eligibility for Medicaid and the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 23:24:55 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-23-24-55.wav" length="1396410" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>29</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-23-24-55.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>New Mac models through 2026 revealed in leaked Apple identifiers</title>
      <description><![CDATA[New Mac models through 2026 revealed in leaked Apple identifiers

Apple still has plenty of new product launches coming through the rest of the year, including at least two Macs. But today, a new report has outlined Mac models coming not only in 2025, but even those expected through 2026.

Marko Zivkovic writes at AppleInsider:

Through our own data and information shared with us, AppleInsider has learned of 15 new Mac models currently in development. People familiar with the matter — and common sense — have told us that Apple plans to introduce its M5 chip within a matter of months, and that M6-equipped devices could see some significant changes in late 2026.

Apple’s product identifiers follow a pattern, so it is easy to figure out which identifier belongs to which future Mac. The following Macs are expected to be released in the next year, though exact release windows mentioned in this report are based on rumors and Apple’s expected schedule.

The full report walks in detail through the variety of Apple identifiers for forthcoming Mac models that AppleInsider obtained.

Here are some of the highlights:

Many of these forthcoming models come as no surprise, as Apple has generally followed set norms for Mac upgrades with M-series chips.

However, the one detail that stood out as most significant to me involves the identifiers for next year’s M6 MacBook Pro models.

Apple uses ‘K114’ and ‘K116’ identifiers for those models, with the last digits referencing screen sizes.

Thus, it seems that despite the big rumored hardware redesign, next year’s MacBook Pro will still come in the same 14-inch and 16-inch sizes.

The last time the MacBook Pro got a new design, its displays changed from 13- and 15-inch to the current 14- and 16-inch options.

But it looks like the next redesign will keep screen sizes about the same, even if lots of other things change.

What stood out to you most about Apple’s 2025-2026 Mac plans? Let us know in the comments.

FTC: We use income earning auto affiliate links. More.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:35:31 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-00-35-31.wav" length="6507044" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>135</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-05-00-35-31.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-00-35-31.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Postpone Your Pleasures</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Postpone Your Pleasures

Want to stay current with Arthur’s writing? Sign up to get an email every time a new column comes out.

My father-in-law, with whom I was very close, spent most of his life on the same working-class street in Barcelona’s El Clot neighborhood. Born in 1929, he saw Spain’s bloody civil war taking place literally in front of his house. His family experienced a lot of suffering. Some died; others spent years in jail or were forced into exile. He himself spent a year in a refugee camp, an experience that affected him for the rest of his life. Every time he wanted to make a point about society or culture, he always started with: “Well, during the civil war …”

One evening, a few months before he died, he read in his local paper an article of mine about unhappiness. “You have a lot of complicated theories,” he told me, “but the real reason people are unhappy is very simple.” I asked him to elaborate. “They don’t enjoy their dinner,” he responded. I asked him what he meant. “Well, during the civil war, we were always hungry,” he said. “But one day a year—Christmas—we got to eat whatever we wanted, and we were so happy. Today, people snack all day long, are never hungry, don’t enjoy their dinners, and aren’t happy—even on Christmas.”

That is a somewhat reductive hypothesis about global unhappiness, to be sure. But he was not wrong in his main contention: Happiness rises, paradoxically, when you do not get whatever you want, whenever you want it. Rather, well-being requires that you discipline your will and defer your gratifications. Understanding this and taking action to change your habits can make you a much happier person.

Read: The politics of a long-dead dictator still haunt Spain

In the behavioral sciences, the most famous study of deferred gratification is the so-called marshmallow experiment undertaken in 1970 by the psychologists Walter Mischel and Ebbe B. Ebbesen. This research project brought 32 young children into a laboratory, where they were offered either animal crackers or pretzel sticks (the marshmallow was an option that came only in later experiments). Before they were allowed to eat the treat, however, the researchers offered an upgrade: If the children could wait by themselves for 15 minutes without eating the snack, they would get a second one. All of the kids accepted the deal, and the researchers left the room and observed each child through a one-way mirror. Ten subjects succeeded in waiting and got the additional snack; 22 of them gave in to their desire and gobbled up the treat before the 15 minutes had elapsed.

Mischel and his colleagues were interested in the long-term differences between kids who were able to defer their gratification and those who weren’t, so they followed the participants as they grew up. In papers published decades later, the psychologists found that the two groups diverged significantly. For example, the ones who waited went on to get significantly higher scores on their SAT exams. Those who didn’t wait used drugs more frequently in adolescence and got less education. The researchers’ conclusion was clear: Being able to defer gratification leads to a more successful—and ultimately more satisfying—life.

As is the case for much research in behavioral science, these conclusions were later contested, by scholars who used larger, more diverse samples of kids and methods that carefully controlled for family background and cognitive ability. For example, one 2018 study concluded that being able to delay gratification has by itself only a weak effect on educational outcomes, and is insignificant in predicting anti-social behavior. Although these revised findings suggest that being able to say no to your immediate desires might not be a universal panacea, newer research has shown that a capacity to defer gratification does consistently deliver one important increase: in well-being. For example, scholars writing in 2014 in the Journal of Personality showed that people who score a high level of self-control enjoy significantly better mood and life satisfaction than those who lack such self-discipline.

One practical example of this happiness effect involves materialistic values and how people spend money: As I have previously written, borrowing money (for discretionary consumption) lowers happiness, whereas saving raises it. You might predict from that finding that people who see money as a sign of success would likely be savers who prefer to delay gratification. Yet on the contrary, two psychologists demonstrated in a 2017 study that people who regard money as the measure of success tend to be spenders: When they have money, they typically use it immediately to acquire things—because they identify having possessions as a source of happiness. The researchers found that these people were less happy than people who didn’t behave this way.

To what degree the ability to defer gratification is down to nature or conditioned by nurture is unclear, but what we do know—because neuroscientists have demonstrated it—is that those who postpone their pleasure exhibit different brain activity when facing temptation from those who want to get their jollies right away. One study, from 2011, showed that people good at delaying indulgence have more activity in the prefrontal cortex (indicating that executive decision-making is taking place) when doing so than people who give in to their desire more easily, who in turn have more activity in the ventral striatum (a region that processes reward). Suggestive also are animal studies that have shown how mice taught to delay a reward enjoy a smoother, more regulated dopamine release than mice without this skill.

Read: Why rich kids are so good at the marshmallow test

Although the evidence is mixed on the long-term implications of the marshmallow test, being able to defer gratification is clearly valuable for well-being. Even if some people may be naturally better at postponing rewards, we also have some evidence that the skill can be cultivated from an early age. If this is something you could work on, here are two ways to get started. They may appear contradictory, but done right, they in fact complement each other.

1. Think about the future. A research-proven approach to improving your capacity for deferred gratification is to imagine yourself in the future. In 2011, a team of researchers interested in how to elicit saving behavior employed digital aging techniques and virtual reality to enable people to interact with elderly versions of themselves. They found that after doing so, the participants were more willing than other people to accept awards of money at a future date rather than immediately.

You can use this finding in creative ways. For example, if you are hankering for a portion of junk-calorie carbohydrates at 4 p.m., have a conversation with a 6 p.m. version of yourself who forwent the snack and is hungry for a good healthy dinner. Or say you are in college and have a big exam tomorrow but have just gotten invited to a party: Have a chat with the unhappy future you who took the exam after partying instead of studying.

2. Don’t think about the future. Paradoxically, a second technique for delaying gratification is to stop thinking about the future, in the form of purposeful mindfulness, the practice of paying attention nonjudgmentally to the present moment. Scholars in 2018 undertook an experiment in which a group of participants were asked to complete a survey of their willingness to defer rewards. Half of the group were then given an exercise in mindfulness breathing, while the other half (the control group) watched a music video. Afterward, when both groups retook the survey, the mindfulness practitioners were significantly more likely than before to defer rewards (whereas the music-video watchers showed no change).

Despite any initial impression otherwise, this second result is not at odds with the first finding: Its conclusion is that being more conscious when you make decisions will lead you to optimize your choices. So you can bring the two injunctions together and combine them to best effect: Think clearly about what you’re doing right now, and then think clearly about how you will reflect on your action later.

So before you buy that sweater, think about how you are feeling at this moment. Do you really need this sweater, or are you just self-soothing with a bit of retail therapy? Next, imagine yourself looking at the sweater in two months’ time. Does it give you delight or remind you that you have to make a credit-card payment?

Arthur C. Brooks: Four rules for identifying your life’s work

My father-in-law was right that deferring gratification leads to greater happiness. The good news is that you don’t need to be in the middle of a civil war to make this skill worth cultivating. But I always wondered whether he was right in his specific example: Does snacking lower well-being by ruining your enjoyment of proper meals? I have been unable to find any studies of this precise curiosity, so I had to triangulate some related research findings to come to a convincing answer.

Researchers who were studying the eating behavior of children reported in 2017 in the Journal of Nutrition Education and Behavior that kids enjoyed food more when they followed structured meal settings—such as eating at the same times each day and dining in a family setting. They also tended to be less fussy about what they were eating. This is broadly supportive of my father-in-law’s theory. And I certainly never saw him eat a snack.

What I did see, however, was his complete unwillingness to save money and a reckless openhandedness about spending it. And this negative example supported his theory even more—though in a sad way, as he constantly ducked creditors and struggled to meet his basic needs in old age. Perhaps the inability to save was also an effect of the privations of his 1930s childhood: If you never know whether you’ve got enough to get through the month, why save the money you have now? Even though he suffered as a result of his spendthrift ways, I took a valuable lesson from his example in this too.

So my seasonal advice: Go to your holiday dinner good and hungry. But don’t buy your holiday feast on credit.

By Arthur C. Brooks]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:40:00 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-00-40-00.wav" length="29734244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>619</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-05-00-40-00.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-00-40-00.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Cyberpunk Edgerunners 2 will be even sadder and bloodier</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Cyberpunk Edgerunners 2 will be even sadder and bloodier

In May, we learned that the development of a sequel to the Cyberpunk 2077 game is moving forward at CD Projekt Red, and today, at the Anime Expo 2025 event, it officially announced a new season of the anime spinoff for Netflix. Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2 will have “…an entirely new story, fresh characters, and a raw, realistic take on the most dangerous city of the dark future.

The new season will be directed by Kai Ikarashi, who also directed episode six in the first season, “Girl on Fire.” There’s no word yet on when Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2 will premiere, but they did show off this new poster artwork. A trailer will be shown later tonight during a panel at 8:30PM PT for the animation studio, Trigger.

Showrunner and writer Bartosz Sztybor said during Friday’s panel that for season one, “I just wanted to make the whole world sad… when people are sad, I’m a bit happy,” and that this new 10-episode season will be “…of course, sadder, but it will be also darker, more bloody, and more raw.”

A brief summary of the follow-up series tells fans what to expect following the end of David’s story in season one:

Cyberpunk: Edgerunners 2 presents a new standalone 10-episode story from the world of Cyberpunk 2077— a raw chronicle of redemption and revenge. In a city that thrives in the spotlight of violence, one question remains: when the world is blinded by spectacle, what extremes do you have to go to make your story matter?

By Richard Lawler]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 15:01:58 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-15-01-58.wav" length="4664444" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>97</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-05-15-01-58.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-15-01-58.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>ℹ️ AUDIO_GENERATION_FAILURE: Failed to generate audio</title>
      <description><![CDATA[ℹ️ AUDIO_GENERATION_FAILURE: Failed to generate audio

ℹ️ AUDIO_GENERATION_FAILURE: Failed to generate audio for title: 'Meet Soham Parekh, the engineer burning through tech by working at three to four startups simultaneously'. Error: The request timed out.
---------- ERROR ----------
The request timed out.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 15:04:46 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-15-04-46.wav" length="411450" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>8</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-15-04-46.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>The Ploopy Knob is an open-source control dial for your PC</title>
      <description><![CDATA[The Ploopy Knob is an open-source control dial for your PC

Ploopy has announced another desktop accessory called the Ploopy Knob that can function like a control dial for adjusting volume, scrolling documents, or scrubbing through media on a computer. The Canadian company isn’t exactly a household name like Logitech, but Ploopy’s open-source peripherals offer a lot of customizability, and like its mouse and trackballs, you can customize the look of the Knob by 3D-printing your own hardware.

The Ploopy Knob is available now through the company’s website for $49.99 CAD (around $37). Unlike many of the company’s other products, which can be purchased as cheaper DIY kits you build yourself, the Knob is only available as a fully assembled product with software preinstalled that works right out of the box. However, since it’s open-source, you can download all the design files and software on Ploopy’s GitHub page if you want to source the parts and build your own from scratch.

Powered by a Raspberry Pi RP2040 microcontroller, the Ploopy Knob uses a position sensor with a 12-bit resolution and a polling rate of over 1kHz to track its rotational movements. The company says the Knob supports high-resolution pixel-by-pixel scrolling on Windows and Linux, but warns that the experience may not be as smooth on Apple computers. “macOS does smoothing for input devices automatically. This interferes with the code that runs on the Knob, meaning that pixel-by-pixel high-resolution scrolling doesn’t work on macOS. It still functions as a scrolling device, but the scrolling is in discrete steps.”

As with the company’s other peripherals, the Ploopy Knob uses the open-source QMK firmware, which runs entirely on the device so you don’t need to install additional software on your computer.

By Andrew Liszewski]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 15:08:49 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-15-08-49.wav" length="5589690" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>116</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-05-15-08-49.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-15-08-49.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>How to Find Joy in Your Sisyphean Existence</title>
      <description><![CDATA[How to Find Joy in Your Sisyphean Existence

“How to Build a Life” is a column by Arthur Brooks, tackling questions of meaning and happiness. Click here to listen to his podcast series on all things happiness, How to Build a Happy Life.

Sisyphus, the king of Ephyra, was renowned in Greek mythology for his ingenuity; indeed, so clever was he that he cheated death twice, angering the gods. They took their revenge by condemning Sisyphus to eternal torment in the underworld: He had to roll a huge boulder up a hill. When he reached the top, the stone would roll back down to the bottom, and he would have to start all over, on and on, forever.

Nowadays, any task combining boredom, struggle, stress, and futility might be labeled “Sisyphean.” Think of so-called duct-tapers in customer service, who are tasked to deal with angry people all day, while the conditions that create those aggressive customers never change. I’ve used the word to describe my former job as a French-horn player in a professional symphony orchestra (which was approximately 99 percent boredom, 1 percent terror). One could even argue that all of life is Sisyphean: We eat to just get hungry again, and shower just to get dirty again, day after day, until the end.

Absurd, isn’t it? Albert Camus, the philosopher and father of a whole school of thought called absurdism, thought so. In his 1942 book The Myth of Sisyphus, Camus singles out Sisyphus as an icon of the absurd, noting that “his scorn of the gods, his hatred of death, and his passion for life won him that unspeakable penalty in which the whole being is exerted toward accomplishing nothing.” If that doesn’t make you want to reach for a filterless cigarette, I don’t know what will.

It would be easy to conclude that an absurdist view of life rules out happiness and leads anyone with any sense to despair at her very existence. And yet in his book, Camus concludes, “One must imagine Sisyphus happy.” This may seem impossible, but in fact, this unexpected twist in Camus’ philosophy of life and happiness can help you change your perspective and see your daily struggles in a new, more equanimous way.

Endless suffering and unhappiness are centered as the overarching themes of life in philosophies from East to West. The first Noble Truth of Buddhism is that life is suffering. Likewise, the 17th-century Christian philosopher Blaise Pascal wrote of our “constant unhappiness” and futile efforts to fight it: “Men seek rest in a struggle against difficulties; and when they have conquered these, rest becomes insufferable.” In both traditions, happiness is but a brief punctuation to the sad rhythm of life.

With his absurdist views, you’d think Camus would endorse such a perspective of the natural awfulness of life. But he doesn’t—quite the contrary. In The Myth of Sisyphus, he acknowledges the futility of Sisyphus’s task, and its obvious parallels in our ordinary lives. But he argues that despite the hardships of this world, against all apparent odds, human beings regularly experience true happiness. People in terrible circumstances bask in love for one another. They enjoy simple diversions. Even Sisyphus was happy, according to Camus, because “the struggle itself toward the heights is enough to fill a man’s heart.” Simply put, he had something to keep him busy.

Read: The game show that parodies your to-do list

This conclusion leads Camus to a strategy for life that is utterly at odds with most of the existentialist philosophers of the past two centuries. Instead of feeling desperation at the futility of life, Camus tells us to embrace its ridiculousness. It’s the only way to arrive at happiness, the most absurd emotion of all under these circumstances. We shouldn’t try to find some cosmic meaning in our relentless routines—getting, spending, eating, working, pushing our own little boulders up our own little hills, he says. Instead, we should laugh uproariously at the fact that there is no meaning, and be happy anyway. Happiness, for Camus, is an existential declaration of independence. Instead of advising “Don’t worry, be happy,” he offers a rebellious “Tell the universe to go suck eggs, be happy.”

If embracing the ridiculous seems impossible to you, Camus says it’s only because of your pride. “Those who prefer their principles over their happiness, they refuse to be happy outside the conditions they seem to have attached to their happiness,” he wrote some years after his essay on Sisyphus. Further, “if they are happy by surprise, they find themselves disabled, unhappy to be deprived of their unhappiness.” The practical advice that follows is clear: If you have an inexplicable moment of happiness in a difficult world, don’t overthink it.

We should be able to do better than relying on serendipity for occasional happiness. In fact, each of us can consciously implement Camus’ absurdism in order to forge a happier life. Here are three practical ways to find joy in the ridiculous.

When you feel existential dissatisfaction—that sense that everything is meaningless—giving up can feel like the easiest course of action. But this is where Camus’ call to rebel should really kick in. You can’t necessarily change your perception of the world, but, as I have written, you most certainly can change your response to that perception. Meet that feeling of despair with a personal motto, such as “I don’t know what everything means, but I do know I am alive right now, and I will not squander this moment.” Say it out loud so you can comprehend it fully and consciously.

Read: When you can’t change the world, change your feelings

One of the best ways to cultivate futility is by focusing on the big things you can’t control—war, natural disasters, hatred—as opposed to the little things you can. Those little things include bringing a small blessing or source of relief to others. For example, if your commute to work is a soul-sucking existential nightmare, don’t ruminate on the cars stopped ahead of you. Rather, focus on making space for that poor sap stuck in the wrong lane who’s desperately trying to merge. If you’re sitting at your desk wondering whether anyone would notice if you stopped doing your job, bring the colleague in the next cubicle a fresh cup of coffee, and enjoy the small delight that small kindness brings both of you.

Absurdity tends to sting only when we see it from the “outside”; for example, when you think about how meaningless it has been to wash the dishes every day in the past only to find them dirty again right now—and imagine the countless dish washings that the rest of your life will comprise. Confronting the absurd is much more comfortable when you do so with mindfulness. This is the point that the Vietnamese Buddhist monk Thich Nhat Hanh made when he wrote, “While washing the dishes one should only be washing the dishes, which means that while washing the dishes one should be completely aware of the fact that one is washing the dishes.” When the broad sweep of life brings you horror, concentrate on this moment, and savor it. The pleasure and meaning you can find right now are real; the meaninglessness of the future is not.

You may not agree with Camus’ core assumptions about the world. I, for one, believe that life is not meaningless, and that there is a cosmic purpose to my work and yours, that love and life will transcend this mortal coil. I believe that we have a divine nature that endows my existence and yours with transcendental meaning.

But on my bad days, well … I doubt all that. Some mornings, I wake up seeing only boulders and can’t face pushing them once again up that hill. I suppose I could stay in bed, contemplating one of Kierkegaard’s more depressing existentialist axioms: “With every increase in the degree of consciousness, and in proportion to that increase, the intensity of despair increases: the more consciousness the more intense the despair.” But staying in bed thinking about that seems even more Sisyphean.

Read: What it’s like to visit an existential therapist

Those are the days when my old friend Camus comes in handy. Instead of despairing of the absurdity of life, I lean into it, laugh at it, and start my day in a light mood. Then I gather my beloved boulders and set out for the nearest hill.

By Arthur C. Brooks]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 17:15:55 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-17-15-55.wav" length="41061092" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>465</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-05-17-15-55.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-05-17-15-55.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>What’s the Most Common Source of Awe?</title>
      <description><![CDATA[What’s the Most Common Source of Awe?

What was a memorable moment of awe in your life?

In a study I conducted with collaborators Yang Bai and Maria Monroy (under review), we provided people with the definition of awe—“being in the presence of something vast and mysterious that transcends your current understanding of the world”—and then they wrote their own stories of awe.

The participants were from 26 countries, including adherents to all major religions, as well as denizens of more secular cultures (e.g., Holland). Our participants varied in terms of their wealth and education. They lived within democratic and authoritarian political systems. They held egalitarian and patriarchal views of gender. They ranged in their cultural values from the more collectivist (e.g., China, Mexico) to the more individualistic (e.g., the United States).

Speakers of 20 languages at UC Berkeley translated the 2,600 narratives they produced. We were surprised to learn that these rich narratives from around the world could be classified into a taxonomy of awe, the eight wonders of life, from collective rituals to sudden intellectual epiphanies.

What most commonly led people to feel awe? Nature? Spiritual practice? Listening to music? In fact, it was other people’s courage, kindness, strength, or overcoming—actions of strangers, roommates, teachers, colleagues at work, people in the news, characters on podcasts, and our neighbors and family members. Around the world, we are most likely to feel awe when moved by moral beauty: exceptional virtue, character, and ability, marked by a purity and goodness of intention and action.

Over 95% of the moral beauty that stirred awe worldwide was in actions people took on behalf of others. Acts of courage are one kind of moral beauty with sublime potential. People using CPR to revive victims of heart attacks, parents raising children with serious health conditions, bystanders interrupting crimes or defusing fights, and organizations like Doctors Without Borders all inspire awe. Here is a story of lifesaving, courageous awe from Chile when a 17 year old went fishing with his brother and friend:

The line got stuck meters into the lagoon. Our friend jumped into the water to free the nylon and started sinking so started yelling for help, my brother despite not being a good swimmer he jumped in to save him. The moment my friend felt my brother’s body, he clung to him by his waist so both of them started drowning. . . . Out of nowhere, a man in a bathing suit came running, jumped into the water and saved both of them. It was a miracle that the person was there.

Others’ kindness was evocative of awe around the world: having car repairs paid for by a restaurant owner; being given money by friends when broke; seeing citizens assist strangers in the streets; reading about moral exemplars, most frequently the Dalai Lama. This story from the United States combines courage with compassion:

1973 at my cousin’s restaurant. My father worked there as a bartender. I was there and my best friend from high school walked in. He is Black and I am white and I had not seen him in five years. I stood and embraced him and we began to talk. A guy at the bar said to my father, “How can you allow your son to have a N as his friend?” My father looked at this guy and loudly told him to get out of his bar and never come back. I have never been more proud of my father, who was 59 years old at that time.

Overcoming obstacles was a universal as well: People thriving despite profound racism and poverty. Jews who had survived the concentration camps. People who transcend mental and physical challenges, as in this story from South Africa:

When watching my daughter, who was born with bilateral club foot, dance in a ballet recital for the first time I was filled with awe. . . . I felt the beginning of tears in my eyes and my heart felt like it was going to burst with pride. I had flashbacks of the time when she was born with her feet upside down and I felt awestruck by how far she has come since that day years ago.

We often turn to literature, to poetry, to film, to art, and, on occasion, to the news for inspiring stories of overcoming and goodness. Here is such an example from Norway:

When I read an article in the paper about an eight year old girl in Yemen who had run away from a forced marriage and taken up the fight against her parents in the judicial system. It hit me how much courage and fighting spirit that can live in a person, and that you can fight for your cause and actually make a change.

Finally, others’ rare talents brought people awe around the world. For a young man from Mexico, it was the trapeze artist and contortionist in the Cirque du Soleil. For a woman in Sweden, her husband’s strength in moving large household objects around the home. For an Australian, watching swimmer Sun Yang’s last 100 meters in a 1,500-meter world-record swim. For another Australian, watching surfers ride 50-foot waves. For a student in Japan, listening to a talk by a Fields Medal–winning mathematician.

Parents’ stories about their children were also common—listening to a fetus’s heartbeat, hearing a one year old’s first word, seeing a two year old gallop, being in the audience at a grammar school dance performance. Children are small, but their development is vast, and a source of awe for parents on their better days.

Everyday moral beauty can transform lives. Steven Czifra grew up in a home that was so violent that one night one parent threw boiling water on the other; he doesn’t remember who it was. He dropped out of school at 10, got into drugs, shaved his head, and ran with a Mexican gang. One day he broke into a parked Mercedes to steal its stereo the very moment the owner, who happened to be an LAPD officer, arrived.

It was everyday moral beauty that transformed him. In solitary confinement in prison, he encountered a knowing librarian who fed Steven’s hunger for reading. Upon his release from prison, at a halfway house, Steven tells me, a biker got him off drugs and a job clearing brush for $70 a day. More moral beauty. Later, at a community college, a Shakespeare teacher named Larry taught Steven to read Milton like a literary critic, and that the self-loathing in his mind was just that, thoughts, fleeting notions from parents who could have done better. Steven, now in graduate school, would cofound the Underground Scholars Initiative at UC Berkeley. This is a network of formerly incarcerated students guiding people in prison and just out to make their way to college.

Within the study of morality, it has long been the view that we find our moral compass in the teaching of abstract principles, the study of great texts, or the leadership of charismatic gurus and great sages. In fact, we are just as likely to find our “moral law within” in the awe we feel for the wonders of others nearby.

From Awe by Dacher Keltner. Reprinted by arrangement with Penguin Press, a member of Penguin Group (USA) LLC, A Penguin Random House Company. Copyright © Dacher Keltner, 2023.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 11:39:54 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-06-11-39-54.wav" length="35925184" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>407</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-06-11-39-54.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-06-11-39-54.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>#124: Vaping as metaphor</title>
      <description><![CDATA[#124: Vaping as metaphor

Good morning!

Today’s Dear Baby covers the psychological nuisance of an old crush (or really any thought we’d rather not entertain), what to do when you hate your partner’s habit (in this case, vaping), and what to do when the path you set out for yourself is all wrong and now you feel deficient (featuring, of all things, birth order theory). Dear Danny is very much happening but on a week delay since I currently have covid and had to cancel our recording. Will publish that next Tuesday, 12/6! Which means there’s still time to submit a question in writing here or by voicemail at 802-404-BABY.

Also, wanted to say thanks so much for joining the extremely fascinating discussion thread on “getting work done” this past Tuesday, a little followup to my Sunday essay on cosmetic procedures (including some additional thoughts on, sorry in advance, Emrata). I’m always getting texts from friends when I do these threads about how eloquent and smart everyone who comments is, and I want to say thank you for making me look good, lol. Really though, there were so many great ideas and anecdotes I’m still thinking about! Feeling grateful and, actually in this case, humbled (but in the real way, not the fake award-speech way).

“I’m having trouble cleansing my subconscious of a girl that I was friends with growing up. I was always infatuated with her but it never amounted to anything serious between us, though we both showed interest from time to time. This continued from about age 13 until college. Both of us are married to other people now and have kids. I love my wife and everything about my life, and never run into this youthful crush anymore IRL. Still, every couple of months, I’ll have a dream about this girl, and in the dream, those feelings I used to have reappear. I always feel guilty when I wake up. Why is it taking so long to shake this attraction and what can I do to move on?”

Dreaming about a former crush is one of the best kinds of dreams, in my opinion. I had a dream about my ex just the other day. In it, he had ridiculously long hair that I inexplicably found beautiful and we were reuniting and making out and I was thrilled. When I woke up, the details already fading, I wasn’t bothered by the dream at all. I’m happy where I am now. No random sequence of old synapses is up to the task of convincing me otherwise. From the sounds of it, you’re happy where you are, too. It’s not your fault this girl, with whom you experienced a formative connection over many years, exists in the recesses of your mind. It’d be strange if she didn’t. The real problem, then, isn’t the dream, but the guilt.

I know I’m always circling this point—care of Alan Watts’s “backwards law”—but so often the root of our problems isn’t the way we feel, but the fact that we’re afraid or ashamed to feel the way we do, and so we spend a bunch of energy avoiding it and accidentally emphasizing it in the process. You’re doing the same thing: emphasizing these dreams by fearing their implications. But what if they don’t imply anything? What if it’s totally fine to dream about this girl? Or even to miss her sometimes, or feel a gentle tug of longing for the life you used to share with her, or the version of yourself that knew her better? Those feelings all sound perfectly normal to me. No matter how happy any of us are with our lives or choices, we’re complicated beings, full of memories and roads not taken. It’d be absurd if we never pondered them. Longing is, I think, a natural human state. It also makes for great art.

If I were to guess, your guilt around these dreams is, ironically, making them occur more frequently. I get a lot of questions from people in relationships concerned over having crushes on other people, and I think they’re in a similar bind. A crush, in my opinion, is merely a prism for projection. If we don’t waste all our energy policing them, they can offer insight: into what we want, miss, need, like. They don’t actually have to mean much more than that. Fearing them only makes them loom larger. It’s like trying not to think of the number seven because someone told you it would ruin your relationship. Avoidance is a bad strategy. Maybe try writing about the dreams when they happen and exploring how they make you feel. I doubt they’ll reveal some unacknowledged desire you have to abandon your life, but I wouldn’t be surprised if they have something interesting to tell you about yourself and your past. Don’t be afraid to find out what that is.

“Please help me! I can't stop feeling mad about my partner taking up vaping and it's driving me crazy (both his new habit and my reaction to it).

My partner has always been vehemently anti-tobacco, a stance I always assumed extended to vaping as well, but earlier this year I noticed he started borrowing our friends' vapes on nights out with more and more frequency. After a few months it transpired that he had bought his own, something which he had kind of hidden-by-omission from me. For his birthday last month, several friends even bought him vapes as a present. We've had a pretty big argument about the fact that he hid it from me, which was very uncharacteristic of him and our relationship, which has always been very open, honest, and comfortable (we have been together over 5 years). He acknowledged that hiding it was weird, but said he did because he knew I'd be judgy about it. The truth is, I am judgy about it! To me it feels very juvenile for a near-30-year-old to take up vaping without any prior nicotine addiction (like, we're not in Euphoria!), I hate that sickly sweet smell of it, and I'm concerned about him getting addicted to something that we don't really know the long-term consequences of. I honestly would rather he took up socially smoking cigarettes, which I know defies logic. 

All of that being said, at the minute, he's only a 'social vaper' (read: on weekends, on nights out) so I suppose it's relatively harmless, and crucially I don't want to be the type of person that dictates what their partner does. I have been on the receiving end of that and it's horrible. And I am worried that I've slightly done this already here by being so vocal about how much I hate it.

I guess my question is: How can I get over the fact that my partner has picked up a habit I find honestly repulsive (I know that's dramatic! But it's how I feel)? How do I stop subconsciously monitoring whether he's going to vape or not when we're out together? It makes me feel psychotic and I don't like it. I don't care about my friends vaping (and loads of them do), so how do I reach this point of neutrality with regards to my partner? (And, in a quieter voice...do I even have to, or am I at all justified in feeling this way?)

If you choose to answer this, thank you endlessly. I'm genuinely driving myself insane.

Thanks!”]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 12:02:15 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-06-12-02-15.wav" length="34303372" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>388</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-06-12-02-15.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-06-12-02-15.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>It’s Me, Hi, I’m the Problem. I’m 33.</title>
      <description><![CDATA[It’s Me, Hi, I’m the Problem. I’m 33.

I have covered economics for 11 years now, and in that time, I have come to the realization that I am a statistic. Every time I make a major life choice, I promptly watch it become the thing that everyone is doing that year.

I started college in 2009, in the era of all-time-high matriculation rates. When I moved to a big coastal city after graduation, so did a huge crowd of people: It was the age of millennial urbanization. When I lived in a walk-in closet so that I could pay off my student loans (“The yellow paint makes it cheerful!”, Craigslist promised), student debt had recently overtaken auto loans and credit cards as the biggest source of borrowing outside of housing in America.

My partner and I bought a house in 2021, along with (seemingly and actually) a huge chunk of the rest of the country. We married in 2022, the year of many, many weddings. The list goes on.

I am no simple crowd follower. What I am is 32, about to be 33 in a few weeks.

And there are so many of us.

If demographics are destiny, the demographic born in 1990 and 1991 was destined to compete for housing, jobs and other resources. Those two birth years, the people set to turn 33 and 34 in 2024, make up the peak of America’s population.

In 2022, America had 4.75 million 32-year-olds and 4.74 million 31-year-olds, the largest two ages by population.

Source: U.S. Census Bureau

By The New York Times

Thank you for your patience while we verify access. If you are in Reader mode please exit and log into your Times account, or subscribe for all of The Times.

Thank you for your patience while we verify access.

Already a subscriber? Log in.

Want all of The Times? Subscribe.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 12:07:29 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-06-12-07-29.wav" length="9830120" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>111</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-06-12-07-29.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>What’s the Most Common Source of Awe?</title>
      <description><![CDATA[What’s the Most Common Source of Awe?

What was a memorable moment of awe in your life?

In a study I conducted with collaborators Yang Bai and Maria Monroy (under review), we provided people with the definition of awe—“being in the presence of something vast and mysterious that transcends your current understanding of the world”—and then they wrote their own stories of awe.

The participants were from 26 countries, including adherents to all major religions, as well as denizens of more secular cultures (e.g., Holland). Our participants varied in terms of their wealth and education. They lived within democratic and authoritarian political systems. They held egalitarian and patriarchal views of gender. They ranged in their cultural values from the more collectivist (e.g., China, Mexico) to the more individualistic (e.g., the United States).

Speakers of 20 languages at UC Berkeley translated the 2,600 narratives they produced. We were surprised to learn that these rich narratives from around the world could be classified into a taxonomy of awe, the eight wonders of life, from collective rituals to sudden intellectual epiphanies.

What most commonly led people to feel awe? Nature? Spiritual practice? Listening to music? In fact, it was other people’s courage, kindness, strength, or overcoming—actions of strangers, roommates, teachers, colleagues at work, people in the news, characters on podcasts, and our neighbors and family members. Around the world, we are most likely to feel awe when moved by moral beauty: exceptional virtue, character, and ability, marked by a purity and goodness of intention and action.

Over 95% of the moral beauty that stirred awe worldwide was in actions people took on behalf of others. Acts of courage are one kind of moral beauty with sublime potential. People using CPR to revive victims of heart attacks, parents raising children with serious health conditions, bystanders interrupting crimes or defusing fights, and organizations like Doctors Without Borders all inspire awe. Here is a story of lifesaving, courageous awe from Chile when a 17 year old went fishing with his brother and friend:

The line got stuck meters into the lagoon. Our friend jumped into the water to free the nylon and started sinking so started yelling for help, my brother despite not being a good swimmer he jumped in to save him. The moment my friend felt my brother’s body, he clung to him by his waist so both of them started drowning. . . . Out of nowhere, a man in a bathing suit came running, jumped into the water and saved both of them. It was a miracle that the person was there.

Others’ kindness was evocative of awe around the world: having car repairs paid for by a restaurant owner; being given money by friends when broke; seeing citizens assist strangers in the streets; reading about moral exemplars, most frequently the Dalai Lama. This story from the United States combines courage with compassion:

1973 at my cousin’s restaurant. My father worked there as a bartender. I was there and my best friend from high school walked in. He is Black and I am white and I had not seen him in five years. I stood and embraced him and we began to talk. A guy at the bar said to my father, “How can you allow your son to have a N as his friend?” My father looked at this guy and loudly told him to get out of his bar and never come back. I have never been more proud of my father, who was 59 years old at that time.

Overcoming obstacles was a universal as well: People thriving despite profound racism and poverty. Jews who had survived the concentration camps. People who transcend mental and physical challenges, as in this story from South Africa:

When watching my daughter, who was born with bilateral club foot, dance in a ballet recital for the first time I was filled with awe. . . . I felt the beginning of tears in my eyes and my heart felt like it was going to burst with pride. I had flashbacks of the time when she was born with her feet upside down and I felt awestruck by how far she has come since that day years ago.

We often turn to literature, to poetry, to film, to art, and, on occasion, to the news for inspiring stories of overcoming and goodness. Here is such an example from Norway:

When I read an article in the paper about an eight year old girl in Yemen who had run away from a forced marriage and taken up the fight against her parents in the judicial system. It hit me how much courage and fighting spirit that can live in a person, and that you can fight for your cause and actually make a change.

Finally, others’ rare talents brought people awe around the world. For a young man from Mexico, it was the trapeze artist and contortionist in the Cirque du Soleil. For a woman in Sweden, her husband’s strength in moving large household objects around the home. For an Australian, watching swimmer Sun Yang’s last 100 meters in a 1,500-meter world-record swim. For another Australian, watching surfers ride 50-foot waves. For a student in Japan, listening to a talk by a Fields Medal–winning mathematician.

Parents’ stories about their children were also common—listening to a fetus’s heartbeat, hearing a one year old’s first word, seeing a two year old gallop, being in the audience at a grammar school dance performance. Children are small, but their development is vast, and a source of awe for parents on their better days.

Everyday moral beauty can transform lives. Steven Czifra grew up in a home that was so violent that one night one parent threw boiling water on the other; he doesn’t remember who it was. He dropped out of school at 10, got into drugs, shaved his head, and ran with a Mexican gang. One day he broke into a parked Mercedes to steal its stereo the very moment the owner, who happened to be an LAPD officer, arrived.

It was everyday moral beauty that transformed him. In solitary confinement in prison, he encountered a knowing librarian who fed Steven’s hunger for reading. Upon his release from prison, at a halfway house, Steven tells me, a biker got him off drugs and a job clearing brush for $70 a day. More moral beauty. Later, at a community college, a Shakespeare teacher named Larry taught Steven to read Milton like a literary critic, and that the self-loathing in his mind was just that, thoughts, fleeting notions from parents who could have done better. Steven, now in graduate school, would cofound the Underground Scholars Initiative at UC Berkeley. This is a network of formerly incarcerated students guiding people in prison and just out to make their way to college.

Within the study of morality, it has long been the view that we find our moral compass in the teaching of abstract principles, the study of great texts, or the leadership of charismatic gurus and great sages. In fact, we are just as likely to find our “moral law within” in the awe we feel for the wonders of others nearby.

From Awe by Dacher Keltner. Reprinted by arrangement with Penguin Press, a member of Penguin Group (USA) LLC, A Penguin Random House Company. Copyright © Dacher Keltner, 2023.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 12:22:33 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-06-12-22-33.wav" length="35925184" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>407</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-06-12-22-33.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-06-12-22-33.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Meet Soham Parekh, the engineer burning through tech by working at three to four startups simultaneously</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Meet Soham Parekh, the engineer burning through tech by working at three to four startups simultaneously

One name is popping up a lot across tech startup social media right now, and you might’ve heard it: Soham Parekh. On X, people are joking that Parekh is single-handedly holding up all modern digital infrastructure, while others are posting memes about him working in front of a dozen different monitors or filling in for the thousands of people that Microsoft just laid off.

From what social media posts suggest, Parekh is actually a software engineer who seems to have interviewed at dozens of tech startups over the years, while also juggling multiple jobs at the same time. Several startups had this revelation on July 2nd, when Suhail Doshi, founder of the AI design tool Playground, posted a PSA on X, saying:

PSA: there’s a guy named Soham Parekh (in India) who works at 3-4 startups at the same time. He’s been preying on YC companies and more. Beware.

I fired this guy in his first week and told him to stop lying / scamming people. He hasn’t stopped a year later. No more excuses.

Doshi’s post was quickly flooded with replies that included similar stories. “We interviewed this guy too, but caught this during references checks,” Variant founder Ben South said. “Turns out he had 5-6 profiles each with 5+ places he actually worked at.” When asked what tipped him off about Parekh, South told The Verge that his suspicions arose during Parekh’s interview, prompting his team to do a reference check earlier than they usually would. “That’s when we learned he was working multiple jobs,” South said.

Parekh’s resume and pitch email look good at first glance, which helps him garner interest from multiple companies. “He had a prolific GitHub contribution graph and prior startup experience,” Marcus Lowe, founder of the AI app builder Create, told The Verge. “He was also extremely technically strong during our interview process.”

Just one day after this all unfolded, Parekh came forward in an interview with the daily tech show TBPN. Parekh confirmed what many tech startup founders had suspected: he had been working for multiple companies at the same time. “I’m not proud of what I’ve done. That’s not something I endorse either. But no one really likes to work 140 hours a week, I had to do it out of necessity,” Parekh said. “I was in extremely dire financial circumstances.”

Parekh seems to have made a good first impression on many people. Digger CEO Igor Zalutski said his company “nearly hired him,” as he “seemed so sharp” during interviews, while AIVideo.com cofounder Justin Harvey similarly said that he was “THIS close to hiring him,” adding that “he actually crushed the interview.” Vapi cofounder Jordan Dearsley said Parekh “was the best technical interview” he’s seen, but he “did not deliver on his projects.”

The startups that did hire Parekh didn’t seem to keep him around for long. Lowe said that he noticed something was off when Parekh kept making excuses to push back his start date. After telling Lowe that he had to delay working because he had a trip planned to see his sister in New York, Parekh later claimed that he couldn’t start working following the trip because he was sick. “For whatever reason, something just felt off,” Lowe said.

That’s when Lowe visited Parekh’s GitHub profile and realized he was committing code to a private repository during the time he was supposed to be sick. Lowe also found recent commits to another San Francisco-based startup. “Did some digging, noticed that he was in some of their marketing materials,” Lowe said. “I was like, ‘Huh, but he didn’t declare this on his resume. This feels weird.’” Create ended up letting Parekh go after he failed to complete an assignment.

It looks like Parekh even had a stint at Meta. In 2021, the company published a post highlighting his story as a contributor working on mixed-reality experiences in WebXR. In the post, Parekh said that he found “that the best way to get better at software development is to not only practice it but to use it to solve real world problems.” Meta didn’t immediately respond to The Verge’s request for comment.

Parekh’s purported scheme may have been uncovered, but his outlook might not be all bad. Parekh said he landed a job at Darwin, an AI video remixing startup, and the company’s founder confirmed it. “Soham is an incredibly talented engineer and we believe in his abilities to help bring our products to market,” Darwin founder and CEO Sanjit Juneja said in a statement to The Verge.

Update, July 3rd: Added a statement from Darwin.

By Emma Roth]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 12:30:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-06-12-30-13.wav" length="23338348" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>264</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-06-12-30-13.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-06-12-30-13.wav</guid>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>