<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <podcast:guid>5C339F5A-DA10-470C-B3D7-8C210B994FEA</podcast:guid>
    <title>C's txtpod</title>
    <link>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <itunes:author>C</itunes:author>
    <description>A podcast generated by txtpod.</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/icon.png</url>
      <title>Cristian's txtpod</title>
      <link>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod</link>
    </image>
    <itunes:image href="https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/icon.png"/>
    <podcast:location>www.txtpod.com</podcast:location>
    <license>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International</license>
    <atom:link href="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  
            <item>
      <title>Slate Auto’s American-made electric</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Slate Auto’s American-made electric pickup — the one with no paint, no stereo, and no touchscreen — is no longer priced “under $20,000.” The increase is a result of Trump’s “Big, beautiful bill,” which will end the federal EV tax credits on September 30th when signed into law later today. That sub-$20,000 price for the Indiana-built pickup was a big selling point for the EV startup backed by Jeff Bezos, and was only possible after applying the $7,500 tax credit to the retail price. The price promotion was scrubbed from the Slate Auto site as recently as yesterday, according to TechCrunch. The website now shows an expected price of “mid-twenties.” Slate’s under $20,000 price tag for a vehicle it won’t start delivering until late 2026 was always accompanied by an asterisk, with fine print highlighting federal incentives that were “subject to change.” And change was certainly expected: Trump campaigned heavily on the promise to end President Biden’s fictitious “EV mandate,” because electric cars are for socialists in MAGA world. Trump’s embrace of oil and gas, while simultaneously dismantling incentives meant to spur the adoption of EVs and clean energies, is a gift to Chinese makers of electric cars, solar panels, and batteries. The US is now on course to own the past while China is firmly positioned to dominate the future. See More: Electric Cars News Policy Transportation]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:37:57 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-37-57.wav" length="4372244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>91</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-37-57.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>It’s been almost two</title>
      <description><![CDATA[It’s been almost two years since a brand new Apple Watch Ultra model launched, but that drought is almost over. Apple Watch Ultra 3’s release date is fast approaching, here’s when to expect the new model. Last year, Apple did not launch a new Ultra model. Instead, it just released a new satin black titanium finish for the Ultra 2. But reporting from various sources indicates this is the year for a brand new model. Apple Watch Ultra 3 is expected to launch this September. Based on well-established patterns, we can get even more precise with the timing. Apple usually kicks off the fall with a big iPhone and Apple Watch-focused event. The most likely date for that event is right around Monday, September 8. Pre-orders for the Apple Watch Ultra 3 will likely begin that week, with the release date being the following Friday, September 19. Apple’s plans could always change, but it has followed a pretty consistent pattern with previous Apple Watch launches. As a result, an Apple Watch Ultra 3 release date in mid-September is highly likely. Apple Watch Ultra 3 is rumored to include a handful of new features. Apple will likely have several more surprises in store too. First, the Ultra 3 is expected to gain display and chip upgrades that it missed out on last year. When the Apple Watch Series 10 arrived last fall, it included a new LTPO3 OLED display. This enabled more frequent refreshes in always-on mode, plus improved viewing from angles. Apple Watch Ultra 3 should gain the same technology this year. Similarly, the Series 10 debuted a new S10 chip, while the Ultra 2 still has the S9. Expect the Ultra 3 to either get Apple’s S10 or a brand new S11—perhaps with AI optimizations for watchOS 26. Outside of playing catch-up to the Series 10, there are three other brand new features rumored for the Ultra 3: High blood pressure detection Satellite connectivity for Messages 5G cellular New health sensors and connectivity features should make the Apple Watch Ultra 3 a better option than ever for adventurers and explorers. Are you planning to buy an Apple Watch Ultra 3 this year? Why or why not? Let us know in the comments. FTC: We use income earning auto affiliate links. More.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-38-01.wav" length="6903644" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>143</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-38-01.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>For the past two</title>
      <description><![CDATA[For the past two years, Apple has been having a tough time in China. Just recently, the U.S. trade war and local incentives from the Chinese government really got in the way of iPhone sales. However, Apple seems to be regaining control of the situation. As we covered recently, Apple’s extended rough patch in China may finally be easing. Since Q3 2022, the company has posted year-over-year revenue growth in just one quarter, with declines of up to 13% in the others. Not great. Things hit a low point a couple of months ago, at the peak of U.S.–China trade tensions. To make matters worse, local government incentives for domestic brands chipped away at Apple’s market share, making it the only major smartphone maker to report a decline in shipments during Q1. From that point on, things started to look a bit better. iPhone sales picked up (slightly) in April, Apple gave in and joined the Chinese government’s subsidy program, and it started to see early signs of a rebound last month. Now, Counterpoint Research is out with a new report (via CNBC)that doubles down on its earlier indication of a turnaround. It claims that Apple saw an 8% rise in iPhone sales in the quarter ending June, a first in two years. Here’s Ethan Qi, associate director at Counterpoint: “Apple’s adjustment of iPhone prices in May was well timed and well received, coming a week ahead of the 618 shopping festival.” As CNBC explains it: “The 618 shopping festival happens in China every June and e-commerce retailers offer heavy discounts.” The report comes on the heels of Apple’s scheduling of its fiscal Q3 earnings results. It will take place on July 31st, and will cover precisely the months of April, May, and June. FTC: We use income earning auto affiliate links. More.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:39:34 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-39-34.wav" length="5650244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>117</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-39-34.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Social media is full</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Social media is full of images of people plunging into freezing lakes and icy baths, with influencers touting the benefits of cold exposure in one form or another. You may have been wondering what it’s all about and whether should you try it. As a qualified cold-water therapist, allow me to take you through my own journey with the cold – and then I’ll show you how to give it a try. Until recent years, I had little interest in being outdoors, let alone swimming in freezing waters. Pop me on a hot beach with a fruity drink, and I was in my element. This changed, rather drastically, five years ago, starting with the diagnosis of my mother’s terminal cancer. I didn’t realise it at the time, but this news, coupled with a change to my job and months of homeschooling, uncertainty and lockdowns during the COVID-19 pandemic, set me on a path of very poor mental health. Come Christmas 2020, I was completely burnt out. I was prescribed antidepressants and anti-anxiety medication, but they made no difference. I spent a few more months barely coping, when my brother suggested a cold-water dip. This seemed ludicrous: I’d always hated being cold. But after discussing it with my GP, and desperate to give anything a try, I went with my brother to Loch of Clunie, Perthshire in Scotland – his hometown. I felt nervous as I anticipated the freezing cold water rushing into my borrowed wetsuit. Stepping into the loch, I gasped and froze as adrenaline pumped through me. Never one for quitting, I proceeded further until I was in over my shoulders. ‘Jeez, that’s cold, I can’t breathe,’ I gasped. ‘OK, I’m in – I did it. Wow, I did it! That’s amazing.’ It’s a cliché, but it really was as if a switch had been flicked. I realised I had experienced a few moments of controlled thought (aka, mindfulness), a skill I thought I had lost forever to my new, anxiety-ridden brain. I felt proud of myself, and I experienced happiness for the first time in almost a year. I felt compelled to understand my experience. I read reports, research papers and any books that were even loosely based on cold therapy. Although cold water as a medicinal therapy is far from a new concept (notable figures from ancient history, such as Hippocrates, are known to have advocated for it), the formal scientific research into its benefits, including for mental health, is still in its infancy. But the research we do have all points in the same positive direction, and I’ve found this is consistently backed up by anecdotal feedback from my clients. Cold-water therapy, encompassing practices such as cold-water immersion and ice baths, has been associated with several physical health benefits, according to research. This includes improved circulation and reduced inflammation. However, I think it’s the psychological benefits of cold-water therapy that are driving its growing popularity. There are many layers of reported positive effects and attributes. To take a specific example: in 2022, researchers surveyed 53 participants with a range of depression severity levels before and after they took part in an eight-session outdoor swimming course on the North Devon coast. Afterwards, 81 per cent of them felt ‘recovered’, and 62 per cent showed ‘reliable improvement’ to their mental wellbeing. Of course, the key beneficial ingredients are tricky to pin down. Other studies show that simply getting outdoors, being in green and blue spaces, is good for us. If we swim with others, there are the benefits of human connection and community too. However, there is something special about the effects of cold water on the body and mind. Exposure to cold water provokes positive mood changes and brain changes associated with emotional control; it also triggers the vagus nerve (which runs from your brainstem to your abdominal organs). This nerve stimulates the parasympathetic nervous system, which controls the body’s ‘rest and digest’ functions. It’s basically the opposite of fight or flight. Its activation calms us after stress, slowing our heartrate and breathing pattern. This resonates with my personal experience. After my first cold-water dip, it was only on reflection that I realised how focused on the present moment I had been in the freezing water. That is exactly what mindfulness is – being fully present in the moment. I had previously confused mindfulness with an idealised notion of meditation (where one works to clear the mind of all thought). There were most definitely thoughts in my mind, but instead of the usual anxious worries, it was more: What am I doing? This is cold, wow – look at that bird, oh, this feels OK now (you get the idea). It was such a relief to know that I wasn’t broken beyond repair, and I could indeed tear my thoughts away from worry and angst. The cold water demanded it from me. This was followed by the ‘natural high’ that cold-water swimmers rave about. By continually exposing ourselves to a stressor (the cold water) and overcoming the shock, we are also building resilience, a key tool in the toolkit of good mental health. We are learning to manage stress, and this is cross-adaptive to other stressful life scenarios. One of my earliest experiences of this was at my mother’s funeral, for which I had written a poem to read. As I stood, my mind was racing, legs weak, and I couldn’t speak. I took a moment to close my eyes and channel the calmness that I feel when in cold water. I imagined myself in the water, breathed as I would in the cold and, after a minute, was able to talk. Many of my clients have shared similar stories of how they feel better equipped to deal with difficult situations because they have habituated themselves to stress. Do you feel ready to give cold-water therapy a try? Here are some practical steps, starting gently and building up to a cold-water swim. Because cold-water immersion can be dangerous for people with certain medical conditions, please remember to check with your doctor first. Has anyone ever advised you to splash cold water on your face and neck after you’ve been angry, upset or stressed? There’s a scientific reason it might help. The application of cold to the back of the neck is a quick and easy method for stimulating the vagus nerve. A more dramatic effect can be achieved by fully immersing your face in cold water, which triggers the trigeminal nerve (the fifth cranial nerve) in your face, which then signals to your brain that you’re underwater. In turn, this activates the vagus nerve, to slow your heart rate and breathing. This is known as the ‘mammalian dive reflex’. It’s another easy method of using cold water to reduce stress. You will find all sorts of cold-shower plans if you look online, differing depending on the aims. Some people will be using them as a method of acclimatising to the cold – working up to cold-water swimming or ice baths. But you can use your shower as a standalone method of cold exposure. Remember that the calming benefits of cold-water immersion come after the initial shock. That’s why it’s important to develop a practice that works toward you being comfortable in the cold – at least for a short while. Although it might be unavoidable at first, if you jump around and scream and shout the whole time, you’re just staying in the stressor part of the experience, and may not gain the maximum benefits. Take a stopwatch into the shower. Start with a warm shower as normal. Then slowly reduce the water temperature. There is no formal definition of what counts as cold water, but scientists researching cold-water benefits usually take 15°C (60°F) or lower as cold. You may need to work down to this over time. As a rough guide, try turning down the temperature until it feels slightly uncomfortable and triggers a gasp breath. As your gasp reflex kicks in – breathe! Do not practise any form of forced breathwork (this can be highly dangerous in water as you may pass out), but just aim to control your breath. Inhale through your nose and out of your mouth. I often find that a noisy breath helps me to maintain a good pattern. Try to stay under at least until you feel the shock subside. Don’t set yourself a target duration after that, but do have your stopwatch running so you can see how long you were in for. Over time and with daily practice, you will likely notice your initial shock response subsides and that you are able to tolerate the cold for longer. Some say that the best time to take a cold shower is in the morning to kick-start your system. Personally, I find a cold shower more of a challenge than an ice bath or outdoor swim. Maybe it’s because I’m not fully submerged the whole time? Just as soon as the front of my body gets comfortable, I then have to turn round and start all over again on my back! Having your body fully submerged in the cold is the ultimate cold-water exposure. It doesn’t matter whether you’re in the sea, a river, a lake, an outdoor pool (or even a purpose-made ice bath), cold water is cold water. It’s the safety precautions that vary hugely in different bodies of water. Never go alone. Wetsuits are optional. You will still experience some level of cold exposure and, if a neoprene suit helps you to overcome any initial fears, and gets you outdoors, then use it (you can always ditch the suit later for maximum cold exposure). For obvious reasons, it’s often easier to start at the ‘warmer end’ of cold – around 15°C (as a rough guide, this is the kind of temperature you might expect swimming off the Pacific Coast in early summer in the US, or sea swimming in early summer in the UK, or off an Australian beach in the winter). This will help you to acclimatise and prepare gradually for colder temperatures. Try to go weekly as a minimum. There’s no proven research on how regularly you need to participate, but I find once a week is satisfactory, and that two to three times a week is optimal. If I don’t manage to get in the water for two weeks or more, I find that I start to lose some of my tolerance. How cold should you go? Endorphins are the primary natural painkillers in the body and improve mood. It could be suggested that colder water will produce greater endorphins. Many of my clients report a higher state of euphoria after dipping in icy waters, but many of them started their cold-water journeys in warmer water and worked towards ice-dipping. Even after a medical check-up, you never know how your body will react, and the safest advice is to take things gradually and see what works for you. Always enter slowly. Yes, this can feel like more of a challenge, but it will allow you to keep control and put the least pressure on your heart. If you are in a natural body of water, take it in stages. Get your feet in and stand for a moment. Take a controlled breath. Wade in until you’re above the knees. Take a moment – notice the cold and turn to your breath. You may find you’re holding your breath at this stage. Concentrate on breathing in through the nose and out through the mouth. You must be mindful that, although you are not rushing, you also don’t want to take too long to get in. Our bodies lose heat up to 25 times faster in cold water. Next, aim to get waist deep. At the point that some of your most sensitive areas are going to hit the water, inhale, step forward (or crouch lower in your ice bath) and use your out-breath to get them in. The groin, underarms and neck are usually our warmer spots, and the contrast can feel greater. Continue to breathe calmly until any shock or gasp reflex has lessened. Finally, it is your aim to get fully immersed. By this, I mean in up to your neck (do not submerge your head or face when starting out). Again, use your breath, inhale, then plunge down until the water hits your neck on the exhale. Sit with it and maintain your breathing. Once you are breathing normally, you have gone past the stress, and your parasympathetic nervous system is fully activated. If you’re just starting out, this is when you need to be thinking about getting out. Two to three minutes is likely long enough to get over the cold shock response and resume ‘normal’ breathing. Do not try to ‘stay in longer’ than this or challenge yourself to do more. There is really no need when you are simply using the cold as a form of therapy. If at any point it’s too difficult or if you feel unwell, stop immediately. Following cold-water exposure, you must always remove wet clothing, dry yourself and dress immediately. It takes time for the re-warming process to start, and you must support the process. Gentle movement, such as walking, is most effective to help with re-warming. Cold-water exposure can be dangerous and comes with risks. Everyone responds differently. I recommend seeking an experienced, qualified and insured practitioner if you want to undertake an ice bath or outdoor plunge for the first time in low temperatures. As mentioned, everyone should also seek medical approval before participating, but it’s especially important for people with cardiovascular conditions, respiratory issues or cold-related allergies. We work hard to bring you the most trustworthy, expert and up-to-date information on psychology and mental health in our Guides. You can learn more about how we ensure that they are a reliable source of information here. This Guide is provided as general information only. It is not a substitute for independent, professional medical or health advice tailored to your specific circumstances. If you are struggling with psychological difficulties, we encourage you to seek help from a professional source.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:05:18 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-05-18.wav" length="40342244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>840</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-05-18.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>La tensión y la</title>
      <description><![CDATA[La tensión y la incertidumbre marcan la primera sesión del juicio por el crimen de Valentín Moreno. Las versiones ofrecidas por los dos principales acusados no solo son contradictorias, sino diametralmente opuestas, lo que ha sumido la sala en un clima de confusión y expectativa. Mientras Daniel Díaz Mora ha admitido sin rodeos ser el autor material del asesinato, alegando que actuó por orden de Sergio Gutiérrez, este último ha negado tajantemente cualquier implicación y, aún más, asegura no conocer “de nada” al presunto sicario. La distancia entre sus relatos no puede ser más extrema. Por un lado, Díaz Mora, colombiano, ha reconocido que disparó a Valentín Moreno por la espalda. Señalando a Gutiérrez como el intermediario clave y supuesto cooperador necesario en el crimen. Por otro lado, Sergio Gutiérrez, el segundo acusado, ha ofrecido una versión totalmente distinta: asegura que fue engañado y que, lejos de participar en el asesinato, creía estar colaborando con un grupo de colombianos en un asunto vinculado al narcotráfico. Niega rotundamente haber tenido conocimiento del homicidio o haber mantenido relación alguna con Díaz. En el banquillo de los acusados: Daniel Díaz Mora (izquierda) y Sergio Gutiérrez Martín (derecha) entre dos agentes de los Mossos d'Esquadra Crónica Global Seguimientos por una deuda de dinero De este modo, Daniel Díaz Mora, el hombre acusado de asesinar a Valentín Moreno, ha reconocido ante el tribunal y los miembros del jurado que fue él quien le disparó en la nuca, la tarde del 18 de noviembre de 2021. Durante su declaración ha explicado que un amigo suyo de la infancia, Alexander, le contactó a principios de noviembre de ese año para realizar “un trabajo” en España. Según su versión, Alexander le propuso realizar un seguimiento a una persona a cambio de 5.000 euros, además de cubrir los gastos del viaje. Aceptando, dice, por necesidad económica. Viajó de Medellín a Barcelona, donde se alojó junto a Alexander en un piso cercano a la Sagrada Familia. Al día siguiente de su llegada, ambos conocieron a Sergio Gutiérrez quien les explicó que debían seguir a un individuo por una supuesta deuda de dinero. Ese individuo era Valentín Moreno. Según Díaz Mora, nunca se le habló directamente de un asesinato, sino únicamente de realizar un seguimiento. Monitorizaron la vida de Moreno Según su versión, Sergio les condujo hasta la casa de Moreno, así como al gimnasio y los bares que frecuentaba. Tras conocer los lugares de referencia del objetivo se iniciaron las vigilancias. Para evitar levantar sospechas, utilizaron patinetes eléctricos alquilados con un documento de identidad robado, facilitado por Sergio. Fue así como, según su relato de los hechos, Daniel y Alexander monitorearon los movimientos diarios de Moreno mientras iban reportando la información recibida. Valentín Moreno, en círculo rojo, con el resto del equipo del Sant Adrià CF Cedida "Le hago un disparo en la cabeza" Sin embargo, la tarde del 18 de noviembre de 2021, lo que comenzó como una tarea de vigilancia derivó en una ejecución. Según su testimonio, Alexander lo citó cerca del bar que frecuentaba la víctima. En ese momento, y bajo amenazas contra su familia, Díaz Mora accedió a participar en el asesinato. Recibió un maletín con una pistola cargada con silenciador, se subió a una bicicleta y siguió a Valentín durante varias calles. Cuando este salió de su coche, le disparó por la espalda, directamente en la nuca. “Le hago un disparo en la cabeza”, ha reconocido. Tras el crimen, Alexander lo recogió en una motocicleta y se encargó de deshacerse del arma. Ambos se dirigieron a un punto donde los esperaba Sergio, visiblemente alterado. Al día siguiente volvieron a Medellín con unos billetes que ya tenían comprados previamente. Valentín Moreno, el homicida de la Vila Olímpica, durante un juicio EFE La versión del presunto cooperador A continuación ha sido el turno de Sergio Gutiérrez. Visiblemente nervioso, ha comenzado su declaración asegurando que no conoce “de nada” a Daniel Díaz Mora, a quien afirma no haber visto en su vida. En tono tajante, ha acusado al otro procesado de mentir deliberadamente para obtener un pacto con la Fiscalía, que —según ha confirmado— también le ofrecieron a él. Sin embargo, Gutiérrez asegura que no puede aceptar un acuerdo porque no puede admitir un crimen que no ha cometido. En su lugar, ha ofrecido una versión completamente distinta de su implicación en los hechos, una que —según dice— tiene su origen en un asunto relacionado con el narcotráfico. Según su testimonio, tras salir de prisión por una condena vinculada al tráfico de drogas, se puso en contacto con Cristian Rus, con la intención de volver a buscarse la vida en el mundo de la droga. Rus le prometió que hablaría con Javier Gómez, alias Javidubi, para ver si podía echarle una mano. Dos presuntos colombianos narcos Poco después, Cristian Rus le presentó a Gómez, quien se había hecho muy popular por su vinculación con los Boixos Nois. Fue entonces cuando Javidubi le comentó que dos colombianos “muy potentes” iban a llegar a Barcelona por un negocio de narcotráfico, concretamente para controlar una carga en el Puerto de la ciudad. Su función, según declaró, se limitaría exclusivamente a buscarles alojamiento. Así, consiguió un piso turístico en las inmediaciones de la Sagrada Familia, donde se instalarían los supuestos colombianos. Javidubi, quien según Gutiérrez no tenía un rol operativo en el envío, pero sí interés en que todo saliera bien, le advirtió que los recién llegados venían “a controlar el terreno” y a supervisar la llegada de un contenedor. A principios de noviembre, recibió un mensaje: “Ha llegado uno de los colombianos”, le advirtió Javidubi. Quedaron en un bar cercano al piso. Allí, según relató, estaban ya presentes Alexander —la misma persona que Díaz Mora señala como quien le propuso el crimen— y Javi. Gutiérrez llegó algo más tarde. Durante el encuentro, conversaron con discreción sobre temas de “carga y distribución”, sin entrar en detalles. Luego lo acompañó al piso de Sagrada Familia y les ayudó a encontrar un coche con el que moverse por la ciudad. El abogado señala a 'Javidubi' Previamente, durante la intervención de su abogado defensor, este ha recalcado que su cliente no tenía ningún conflicto personal con Valentín Moreno ni interés alguno en su muerte. Sin embargo, ha señalado que sí había al menos dos personas que podrían haber tenido motivos: Cristian Rus y Javier Gómez, Javidubi. El letrado ha insinuado que ambos, que en el pasado habían sido íntimo de Moreno, podrían haber estado más implicados de lo que hasta ahora se ha podido acreditar en el proceso. Tanto Rus como Gómez están citados a declarar este viernes en calidad de testigos.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:37:55 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-37-55.wav" length="23946044" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>498</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-37-55.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>iOS 26’s Messages app</title>
      <description><![CDATA[iOS 26’s Messages app has a solution coming for unwanted texts

Apple’s Messages app got a lot of new features last year, but iOS 26 continues the trend of big upgrades, including a handy solution for all those unwanted spam texts you keep getting. Messages can automatically screen your texts for spam in iOS 26 iOS 26’s Liquid Glass design may be getting the most attention, but the iPhone’s next big update also has lots of new app features coming. These include changes to Apple Wallet, Music, Notes, Reminders, Photos, and more. Apple’s Messages app is getting a big update too. Messages in iOS 26 gets conversation backgrounds, group typing indicators, polls, live translation, and more. One new addition should solve a common frustration for users: unwanted spam texts. As part of Apple’s broader initiative to combat spam outreach, iOS 26 provides the option of silencing texts from unknown numbers and hiding them inside a separate area inside Messages. When using iOS 26, the Messages app will ask you if you’d like to use the new screening tool to filter out texts that are detected as possible spam. If you enable the feature, two changes will take effect: Those texts will no longer alert you via a notification And they’ll get hidden in a separate section of the app Silencing notifications is a great change that limits unwanted interruptions of your time and attention. But you’ll still be able to access those texts if you need to. Via the filtering tool in the top-right corner of Messages, you can switch between different types of texts. Four sections are available: Messages Unknown Senders Spam Recently Deleted iOS 26 offers the option of separately enabling or disabling screening for both Unknown Senders and Spam. Even though texts from unknown senders no longer appear in your main conversations view, you’ll still get a visual prompt on the filters button when there’s a screened text you may want to check. That way, anything mistakenly pushed out of the main view can be discovered before much time passes. Do you plan to use iOS 26’s new spam screening tools in Messages? Let us know in the comments. FTC: We use income earning auto affiliate links. More.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:44:17 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-44-17.wav" length="6844244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>142</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-44-17.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Slate Auto’s electric pickup is no longer ‘under $20,000’ — thanks, Donald</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Slate Auto’s electric pickup is no longer ‘under $20,000’ — thanks, Donald

Slate Auto’s American-made electric pickup — the one with no paint, no stereo, and no touchscreen — is no longer priced “under $20,000.” The increase is a result of Trump’s “Big, beautiful bill,” which will end the federal EV tax credits on September 30th when signed into law later today. That sub-$20,000 price for the Indiana-built pickup was a big selling point for the EV startup backed by Jeff Bezos, and was only possible after applying the $7,500 tax credit to the retail price. The price promotion was scrubbed from the Slate Auto site as recently as yesterday, according to TechCrunch. The website now shows an expected price of “mid-twenties.” Slate’s under $20,000 price tag for a vehicle it won’t start delivering until late 2026 was always accompanied by an asterisk, with fine print highlighting federal incentives that were “subject to change.” And change was certainly expected: Trump campaigned heavily on the promise to end President Biden’s fictitious “EV mandate,” because electric cars are for socialists in MAGA world. Trump’s embrace of oil and gas, while simultaneously dismantling incentives meant to spur the adoption of EVs and clean energies, is a gift to Chinese makers of electric cars, solar panels, and batteries. The US is now on course to own the past while China is firmly positioned to dominate the future. See More: Electric Cars News Policy Transportation]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:46:46 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-46-46.wav" length="8005884" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>90</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-46-46.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Perhaps more tellingly, you’ve</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Perhaps more tellingly, you’ve

Perhaps more tellingly, you’ve also got to completely ignore the camera. The Magic V5’s triple rear camera module rises almost twice as high as Oppo’s, making the phone feel thicker overall as a result. Superior specs, with higher resolution sensors and faster apertures almost across the board, may justify the extra heft, but it does diminish that “world’s thinnest” claim.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:48:20 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-48-20.wav" length="2167636" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>24</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-48-20.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Apple Watch Ultra 3 release date: When to expect the new model</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Apple Watch Ultra 3 release date: When to expect the new model

It’s been almost two years since a brand new Apple Watch Ultra model launched, but that drought is almost over. Apple Watch Ultra 3’s release date is fast approaching, here’s when to expect the new model. Last year, Apple did not launch a new Ultra model. Instead, it just released a new satin black titanium finish for the Ultra 2. But reporting from various sources indicates this is the year for a brand new model. Apple Watch Ultra 3 is expected to launch this September. Based on well-established patterns, we can get even more precise with the timing. Apple usually kicks off the fall with a big iPhone and Apple Watch-focused event. The most likely date for that event is right around Monday, September 8. Pre-orders for the Apple Watch Ultra 3 will likely begin that week, with the release date being the following Friday, September 19. Apple’s plans could always change, but it has followed a pretty consistent pattern with previous Apple Watch launches. As a result, an Apple Watch Ultra 3 release date in mid-September is highly likely. Apple Watch Ultra 3 is rumored to include a handful of new features. Apple will likely have several more surprises in store too. First, the Ultra 3 is expected to gain display and chip upgrades that it missed out on last year. When the Apple Watch Series 10 arrived last fall, it included a new LTPO3 OLED display. This enabled more frequent refreshes in always-on mode, plus improved viewing from angles. Apple Watch Ultra 3 should gain the same technology this year. Similarly, the Series 10 debuted a new S10 chip, while the Ultra 2 still has the S9. Expect the Ultra 3 to either get Apple’s S10 or a brand new S11—perhaps with AI optimizations for watchOS 26. Outside of playing catch-up to the Series 10, there are three other brand new features rumored for the Ultra 3: High blood pressure detection Satellite connectivity for Messages 5G cellular New health sensors and connectivity features should make the Apple Watch Ultra 3 a better option than ever for adventurers and explorers. Are you planning to buy an Apple Watch Ultra 3 this year? Why or why not? Let us know in the comments. FTC: We use income earning auto affiliate links. More.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 19:49:12 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-49-17.wav" length="11790040" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>133</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-19-49-17.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Honor launches the ‘world’s thinnest’ foldable</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Honor launches the ‘world’s thinnest’ foldable

Honor has announced the Magic V5, which it says is the thinnest foldable phone in the world right now — though only if you ignore the raised camera module, and only for its white version. The phone launches today in China, but Honor says an international release is coming “soon.” At 8.8mm thick when folded shut, the V5 is indeed impressively thin, and beats the 8.9mm Oppo Find N5. That 0.1mm difference is imperceptible in practice, though a very slight curvature does help Honor’s phone feel a hair thinner than the Oppo. That’s only true for the phone’s “Ivory White” version though, with the other colors very slightly thicker at 9mm, as their fiber and vegan leather finishes are different to the “special fiber” of the white model. Perhaps more tellingly, you’ve also got to completely ignore the camera. The Magic V5’s triple rear camera module rises almost twice as high as Oppo’s, making the phone feel thicker overall as a result. Superior specs, with higher resolution sensors and faster apertures almost across the board, may justify the extra heft, but it does diminish that “world’s thinnest” claim. When open, the V5’s frame measures 4.1mm, again just beating Oppo’s 4.2mm. It’s worth remembering that neither of these phones are quite as thin as Huawei’s trifold Mate XT when it’s open, dropping to 3.6mm at its thinnest point, a segment that doesn’t have the USB-C port. This battle of the millimeters isn’t new territory for Honor. Before Oppo launched the Find N5 earlier this year, Honor’s Magic V3 was the thinnest foldable on the market. Next week Samsung is expected to reveal a drastically thinner Galaxy Z Fold 7, though it’s likely to be just a little thicker than Honor’s effort. Honor isn’t highlighting it, but the Magic V5 might be the world’s lightest foldable too, or at least seems to share that title with Vivo’s X Fold 5, announced last week — both weigh 217g. If this all sounds like quibbling over a gram here and a fraction of a millimeter there, then that’s because it is. I said back when I reviewed the Oppo Find N5 that it would “mark the start of diminishing returns” for foldable phones, and here we are. Without dropping the USB-C port or adopting an asymmetric design there simply isn’t room for these phones to get meaningfully thinner, so foldable manufacturers are going to have to figure out a new way to generate hype for future launches. Fortunately for Honor, the Magic V5 has strong enough specs to impress regardless. Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 8 Elite powers the phone, together with up to 16GB of RAM and a large 5,820mAh battery. Both screens use 120Hz LTPO OLED panels, there’s wireless charging, and IP58 and IP59 ratings for dust- and water-resistance that’s almost as good as any non-foldable’s. Update, July 2nd: Added confirmation that the non-white models are finished in different materials. See More: Foldable Phones Mobile News Tech]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:12:24 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-12-24.wav" length="15814180" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>179</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-20-12-24.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-12-24.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Paramount Plus slashes prices to $2 for two months</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Paramount Plus slashes prices to $2 for two months

If you’re looking for an affordable way to kick off your July 4th weekend, Paramount Plus has a deal worth checking out. Just in time for the July 17th premiere of the third season of Star Trek: Strange New Worlds, new subscribers can enjoy two months of Paramount Plus Premium (normally $12.99 per month) or Plus Essential (regularly $7.99 a month) for just $0.99 per month as part of the Summer Sale. Either deal includes all the features of the base Paramount Plus Essential plan, but the Paramount Plus Premium plan offers better value by providing extra perks at the same discounted price. Premium grants access to both Paramount Plus and Showtime, so you can stream Star Trek shows as well as Yellowstone prequels 1883 and 1923, Tales of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, The Chi, Dexter, Billions, and Yellowjackets. The plan also includes a wide variety of acclaimed films, ranging from Love Me, Sonic the Hedgehog 3, and Gladiator 2 to classics like The Godfather and Pulp Fiction. Paramount Plus Premium grants you ad-free access to live sports as well as movies and shows from both platforms, including Tales of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, the Yellowstone catalog, Star Trek shows, Sonic the Hedgehog 3, Twin Peaks, Dexter, and more. $1 at Paramount (monthly) What’s more, Paramount Plus Premium will also let you livestream the upcoming 2025 NFL season, watch 24/7 live news from CBS News, and catch UEFA Champions League matches. And unlike the base plan, Premium is ad-free and allows you to download content to your mobile device for offline viewing, making it perfect for streaming on the go. Unfortunately, after the two-month promotion period ends, prices return to normal: $12.99 per month for Paramount Plus Premium or $7.99 for Plus Essential. If you’d rather not pay for either, be sure to set a reminder to cancel. See More: Deals Entertainment Star Trek Streaming Tech TV Shows

By Sheena Vasani]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:22:07 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-22-07.wav" length="11549444" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>130</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-20-22-07.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-22-07.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Microsoft is laying off</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Microsoft is laying off as many as 9,000 employees

Today we are sharing decisions that will impact colleagues across our organization. To position Gaming for enduring success and allow us to focus on strategic growth areas, we will end or decrease work in certain areas of the business and follow Microsoft’s lead in removing layers of management to increase agility and effectiveness. Out of respect for those impacted today, the specifics of today’s notifications and any organizational shifts will be shared by your team leaders in the coming days. I recognize that these changes come at a time when we have more players, games, and gaming hours than ever before. Our platform, hardware, and game roadmap have never looked stronger. The success we’re seeing currently is based on tough decisions we’ve made previously. We must make choices now for continued success in future years and a key part of that strategy is the discipline to prioritize the strongest opportunities. We will protect what is thriving and concentrate effort on areas with the greatest potential, while delivering on the expectations the company has for our business. This focused approach means we can deliver exceptional games and experiences for players for generations to come. Prioritizing our opportunities is essential, but that does not lessen the significance of this moment. Simply put, we would not be where we are today without the time, energy, and creativity of those whose roles are impacted. These decisions are not a reflection of the talent, creativity, and dedication of the people involved. Our momentum is not accidental—it is the result of years of dedicated effort from our teams. HR is working directly with impacted employees to provide severance plan benefits (aligned with local laws), including pay, healthcare coverage, and job placement resources to support their transition. Employees whose roles were eliminated are encouraged to explore open positions across Microsoft Gaming, where their applications will be given priority review. Thank you to everyone who has shaped our culture, our products, and our community. We will move forward with deep appreciation and respect for all who have contributed to this journey. Phil

By Tom Warren]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:41:25 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-41-25.wav" length="6587444" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>137</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-20-41-25.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-41-25.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Google makes it easier</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Google makes it easier to let friends and kids control your smart home

Google Home’s latest update will make it easier to decide who in your household can control your smart home. It comes with a new feature, which Google first started testing last year, that will let you assign people “Admin” and “Member” roles. People with Admin status have full control of all the devices, services, and users within their smart home, while Members can only use “basic” device controls, like watching the live view of a security camera. However, admins can grant Members additional privileges by giving them “Settings” access, allowing for control over device and home-wide settings. Admins can also turn on “Activity” access so Members can keep tabs on device history and recent events, such as a visitor picked up by a doorbell camera. Google is also simplifying the process of adding a child under 13 to the Home app. Once you set up your kid with a Google account through Family Link, you can invite them to your Google Home, which will add them as a Member by default. The previous process involved using either Family Link, Google Home, or Google Assistant settings to add your child’s voice to your smart home before inviting them to your home, and many users struggled to get it to work. It seems Google is now streamlining the process by letting you invite a child to your home through the Google Home app, so long as you add them to your Google family group. See More: Apps Google News Smart Home Tech

By Emma Roth]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 20:44:46 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-44-46.wav" length="4361444" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>90</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-20-44-46.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-20-44-46.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Ultra Mobile raised its data caps without a price increase</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Ultra Mobile raised its data caps without a price increase

T-Mobile is bringing some of its Uncarrier energy to Ultra Mobile, the carrier’s international-focused MVNO that operates on its network. It announced that its plans now have slightly higher data caps and more international perks, but with the same prices as before for new and existing subscribers — a rare thing to see these days. The plan with the most notable increase in data cap is its $39-per-month tier, which jumps from 15GB to 24GB per month. It also includes 5GB of data you can use in Mexico before international data roaming charges kick in. If you’re accustomed to churning through a ton of data every month, its $59-per-month unlimited (talk, text, and data) plan is stuffed with more goodies. It includes a combined $20 in international calling and data roaming credits, plus 25GB to use as a mobile hotspot (it previously included 20GB). You’ll also get 100 minutes to call “nearly anywhere,” and either 500 texts or 500MB of roaming data to use while traveling abroad before you have to pay extra. Whichever plan is best for your budget, Ultra Mobile stands out from Mint Mobile and Metro (other T-Mobile-owned MVNOs), as well as other major carriers, by offering more perks for people who call and text folks in countries outside the US. In addition to unlimited talk and text to Mexico, Canada, and the UK, Ultra allows free calls to landlines and mobile phones in China, India, Australia, and many other countries. Plus, all of its plans support Wi-Fi calling, which makes it easy to take calls even if local coverage is spotty.

By Cameron Faulkner]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 21:00:08 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-21-00-08.wav" length="5223044" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>108</itunes:duration>
              <itunes:image href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/artworks/2025-07-04-21-00-08.jpg"/>
      <guid>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/main/pods/2025-07-04-21-00-08.wav</guid>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>