<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <podcast:guid>5C339F5A-DA10-470C-B3D7-8C210B994FEA</podcast:guid>
    <title>Cristian's txtpod</title>
    <link>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <itunes:author>Cristian</itunes:author>
    <description>A podcast generated by txtpod.</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/icon.png</url>
      <title>Cristian's txtpod</title>
      <link>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod</link>
    </image>
    <itunes:image href="https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/icon.png"/>
    <podcast:location>www.txtpod.com</podcast:location>
    <license>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International</license>
    <atom:link href="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  
            <item>
      <title>I tried that but</title>
      <description><![CDATA[I tried that but not enough for me, I really want something completely automatic without me having to go to the app. Just share and minutes later a new episode in my podcast player.

kinda like this prototype]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 16:55:06 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-16-55-06.wav" length="641444" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>13</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-16-55-06.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>just testing sgain snother</title>
      <description><![CDATA[just testing sgain snother option here with cover msybes]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 17:07:50 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-17-07-50.wav" length="189644" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>3</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-17-07-50.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Apple is suing a</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Apple is suing a former employee for allegedly stealing confidential Vision Pro headset research before leaving to join Snap’s product design team. In the complaint filed in Santa Clara County Superior Court on June 24th, Apple accuses Di Liu of downloading thousands of documents containing proprietary information from Apple’s internal systems and saving them to his personal cloud storage account in his final days as a senior design engineer for the Vision Pro. According to the lawsuit, Liu falsely claimed he was quitting his job for health reasons and did not disclose that he had a new job lined up as a product design engineer for Snap. This prevented Apple from immediately revoking Liu’s access to internal systems, a standard protocol activated by the company upon notice that employees are joining a competitor. Apple alleges that this allowed Liu to copy a “massive volume” of proprietary information that he could later access after being locked out of Apple’s network. “Mr. Liu’s actions were deliberate; logs on his Apple-issued work laptop show that Mr. Liu individually selected the folders he copied and, in some cases, renamed and reorganized them after moving them to his personal cloud storage account,” Apple said in the complaint. “Further, Mr. Liu took actions to conceal movement of the files, intentionally deleting files from his Apple-issued work laptop.” Apple says it’s unable to determine exactly what was downloaded by Liu, but argues the overlap between the information Liu took with Snap’s AR Spectacles products “suggests that Mr. Liu intends to use Apple’s Proprietary Information at Snap.” According to the complaint, Apple is pursuing unspecified financial damages from Liu for breaching contractual obligations and requesting that Liu be forced to return the stolen documents. Apple has not named Snap as a defendant in the suit. Snap said in a statement to SiliconValley that it had reviewed Apple’s claims, and had “no reason to believe they are related to this individual’s employment or conduct at Snap.” This is the latest of several lawsuits that Apple has launched against former employees for misappropriating proprietary information about its products. The company dropped a lawsuit against a former iOS engineer in February and settled its case against a former design architect in 2022 after accusing them of leaking confidential trade secrets to journalists. See More:]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 17:37:34 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-17-37-34.wav" length="6844244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>142</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-17-37-34.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>The iPhone 17 Pro</title>
      <description><![CDATA[The iPhone 17 Pro Max will feature the biggest ever battery in an iPhone, according to the Weibo leaker known as "Instant Digital." In a new post, the leaker listed the battery capacities of the iPhone 11 Pro Max through to the iPhone 16 Pro Max, and added that the iPhone 17 Pro Max will feature a battery capacity of 5,000mAh: iPhone 11 Pro Max: 3,969mAh iPhone 12 Pro Max: 3,687mAh...]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:24:40 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-24-40.wav" length="1747770" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>36</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-24-40.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>It’s been almost two</title>
      <description><![CDATA[It’s been almost two years since a brand new Apple Watch Ultra model launched, but that drought is almost over. Apple Watch Ultra 3’s release date is fast approaching, here’s when to expect the new model. Last year, Apple did not launch a new Ultra model. Instead, it just released a new satin black titanium finish for the Ultra 2. But reporting from various sources indicates this is the year for a brand new model. Apple Watch Ultra 3 is expected to launch this September. Based on well-established patterns, we can get even more precise with the timing. Apple usually kicks off the fall with a big iPhone and Apple Watch-focused event. The most likely date for that event is right around Monday, September 8. Pre-orders for the Apple Watch Ultra 3 will likely begin that week, with the release date being the following Friday, September 19. Apple’s plans could always change, but it has followed a pretty consistent pattern with previous Apple Watch launches. As a result, an Apple Watch Ultra 3 release date in mid-September is highly likely. Apple Watch Ultra 3 is rumored to include a handful of new features. Apple will likely have several more surprises in store too. First, the Ultra 3 is expected to gain display and chip upgrades that it missed out on last year. When the Apple Watch Series 10 arrived last fall, it included a new LTPO3 OLED display. This enabled more frequent refreshes in always-on mode, plus improved viewing from angles. Apple Watch Ultra 3 should gain the same technology this year. Similarly, the Series 10 debuted a new S10 chip, while the Ultra 2 still has the S9. Expect the Ultra 3 to either get Apple’s S10 or a brand new S11—perhaps with AI optimizations for watchOS 26. Outside of playing catch-up to the Series 10, there are three other brand new features rumored for the Ultra 3: High blood pressure detection Satellite connectivity for Messages 5G cellular New health sensors and connectivity features should make the Apple Watch Ultra 3 a better option than ever for adventurers and explorers. Are you planning to buy an Apple Watch Ultra 3 this year? Why or why not? Let us know in the comments. FTC: We use income earning auto affiliate links. More.]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:26:17 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-26-17.wav" length="6903644" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>143</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-26-17.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Slate Auto’s American-made electric</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Slate Auto’s American-made electric pickup — the one with no paint, no stereo, and no touchscreen — is no longer priced “under $20,000.” The increase is a result of Trump’s “Big, beautiful bill,” which will end the federal EV tax credits on September 30th when signed into law later today. That sub-$20,000 price for the Indiana-built pickup was a big selling point for the EV startup backed by Jeff Bezos, and was only possible after applying the $7,500 tax credit to the retail price. The price promotion was scrubbed from the Slate Auto site as recently as yesterday, according to TechCrunch. The website now shows an expected price of “mid-twenties.” Slate’s under $20,000 price tag for a vehicle it won’t start delivering until late 2026 was always accompanied by an asterisk, with fine print highlighting federal incentives that were “subject to change.” And change was certainly expected: Trump campaigned heavily on the promise to end President Biden’s fictitious “EV mandate,” because electric cars are for socialists in MAGA world. Trump’s embrace of oil and gas, while simultaneously dismantling incentives meant to spur the adoption of EVs and clean energies, is a gift to Chinese makers of electric cars, solar panels, and batteries. The US is now on course to own the past while China is firmly positioned to dominate the future. See More: Electric Cars News Policy Transportation]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:31:14 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-31-14.wav" length="4372244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>91</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-31-14.wav</guid>
    </item>
    
            <item>
      <title>Slate Auto’s American-made electric</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Slate Auto’s American-made electric pickup — the one with no paint, no stereo, and no touchscreen — is no longer priced “under $20,000.” The increase is a result of Trump’s “Big, beautiful bill,” which will end the federal EV tax credits on September 30th when signed into law later today. That sub-$20,000 price for the Indiana-built pickup was a big selling point for the EV startup backed by Jeff Bezos, and was only possible after applying the $7,500 tax credit to the retail price. The price promotion was scrubbed from the Slate Auto site as recently as yesterday, according to TechCrunch. The website now shows an expected price of “mid-twenties.” Slate’s under $20,000 price tag for a vehicle it won’t start delivering until late 2026 was always accompanied by an asterisk, with fine print highlighting federal incentives that were “subject to change.” And change was certainly expected: Trump campaigned heavily on the promise to end President Biden’s fictitious “EV mandate,” because electric cars are for socialists in MAGA world. Trump’s embrace of oil and gas, while simultaneously dismantling incentives meant to spur the adoption of EVs and clean energies, is a gift to Chinese makers of electric cars, solar panels, and batteries. The US is now on course to own the past while China is firmly positioned to dominate the future. See More: Electric Cars News Policy Transportation]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:35:58 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-35-58.wav" length="4372244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>91</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-35-58.wav</guid>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>