<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <podcast:guid>5C339F5A-DA10-470C-B3D7-8C210B994FEA</podcast:guid>
    <title>Cristian's txtpod</title>
    <link>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <itunes:author>Cristian</itunes:author>
    <description>A podcast generated by txtpod.</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/icon.png</url>
      <title>Cristian's txtpod</title>
      <link>https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod</link>
    </image>
    <itunes:image href="https://github.com/CristianRus4/txtpod/icon.png"/>
    <podcast:location>www.txtpod.com</podcast:location>
    <license>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International</license>
    <atom:link href="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  
            <item>
      <title>Slate Auto’s American-made electric</title>
      <description><![CDATA[Slate Auto’s American-made electric pickup — the one with no paint, no stereo, and no touchscreen — is no longer priced “under $20,000.” The increase is a result of Trump’s “Big, beautiful bill,” which will end the federal EV tax credits on September 30th when signed into law later today. That sub-$20,000 price for the Indiana-built pickup was a big selling point for the EV startup backed by Jeff Bezos, and was only possible after applying the $7,500 tax credit to the retail price. The price promotion was scrubbed from the Slate Auto site as recently as yesterday, according to TechCrunch. The website now shows an expected price of “mid-twenties.” Slate’s under $20,000 price tag for a vehicle it won’t start delivering until late 2026 was always accompanied by an asterisk, with fine print highlighting federal incentives that were “subject to change.” And change was certainly expected: Trump campaigned heavily on the promise to end President Biden’s fictitious “EV mandate,” because electric cars are for socialists in MAGA world. Trump’s embrace of oil and gas, while simultaneously dismantling incentives meant to spur the adoption of EVs and clean energies, is a gift to Chinese makers of electric cars, solar panels, and batteries. The US is now on course to own the past while China is firmly positioned to dominate the future. See More: Electric Cars News Policy Transportation]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 18:37:57 +1200</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-37-57.wav" length="4372244" type="audio/x-wav"/>
      <itunes:duration>91</itunes:duration>
      <guid>https://CristianRus4.github.io/txtpod/pods/2025-07-04-18-37-57.wav</guid>
    </item>
    </channel>
</rss>